<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[B3RN3D]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-03T03:39:01+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[b3rn3d]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fingerprinting Attacks on Screen Resolution]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/05/29/fingerprinting-resolution/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/05/29/fingerprinting-resolution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.b3rn3d.com/images/fingerprint.png" width="200">Fingerprinting attacks are ways of identifying individuals by some kind of attribute of their online activity. In some ways, fingerprinting attacks are the most dangerous and difficult type of de-anonymizing threats to defend against. I want to highlight one facet of fingerprinting that is used by many web services and organizations: screen resolution tracking.</p>

<p>In many cases, you have a laptop with a native screen resolution. This could be 1024x768, or 1900x1024, or some other combination. These resolutions point to the make and model of your laptop itself. The <a href="https://www.apple.com/macbook-pro/specs/">Macbook Pro</a> for instance has a native resolution of 1280x800. While there are many other laptops that run a similar resolution, you have shrunk down all of the possible systems that could be connecting to that of a system with that resolution. Imagine what a forensic investigator could do with this information.</p>

<p>This is even more dangerous on mobile devices such as Android. Each manufacturer releases new phones and tablets with different resolution, these are often very odd screen resolutions, making them very unique to that phone time. There are dozens of sites that provide this information for you:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_displays_by_pixel_density">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_displays_by_pixel_density</a></li>
<li><a href="https://deviceatlas.com/">https://deviceatlas.com/</a></li>
<li><a href="http://wurfl.sourceforge.net/">http://wurfl.sourceforge.net/</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Background</h2>

<p>There are two types of fingerprinting; passive and active. Active fingerprinting attacks are usually reserved to those that are collecting information about your network traffic, and do a secondary correlation. For example, if an adversary were running multiple exit nodes, they collect the list of sites each circuit connects to, and tries correlates that to a specific user.</p>

<p>Active attacks will manipulate or inject an identifier into your traffic &mdash; an identifying cookie or malicious JavaScript that when executed tries to collect identifying information about your browsing environment.</p>

<p>This is not a new revelation, the EFF has highlighted this problem by making the <a href="https://panopticlick.eff.org/">Panopticlick</a> project. This simulates attacks that aim at fingerprinting your browser, its plugins, fonts installed, etc. This is similar to the <a href="http://browserspy.dk/">BrowserSpy</a> project.</p>

<h2>Screen Resolution</h2>

<p>While we&rsquo;ve found ways to defend ourself against a variety of attacks (e.g. detecting the plugins we have installed by disabling JavaScript), defending yourself against tracking your screen resolution becomes more difficult. You should note here that screen resolution is the actual resolution of your computer screen, not just your browser window.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s a simple Javascript example that does that</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>&lt;a href="javascript:alert
</span><span class='line'>('Your resolution is '+screen.width+'x'+screen.height);">
</span><span class='line'>Screen Resolution Example&lt;/A></span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Demo: <a href="javascript:alert
('Your resolution is '+screen.width+'x'+screen.height);">
Screen Resolution Detection Example</A></p>

<p>EDIT: <a href="www.reddit.com/user/lugh">lugh</a> points out that this example is inconsistent and depends on your OS and browser.</p>

<h2>Defense Measures</h2>

<p>There are a couple of ways of defending, let me go over some possibilities:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>disabling Javascript</strong>: CSS (AFAIK) does not have a way of detecting your screen resolution</li>
<li><strong>resizing your browser window</strong>: Sometimes attacks do not read screen resolution, but just window size.</li>
<li><strong>changing your screen resolution</strong>: This is often difficult but by choosing a screen resolution that many other users may have, would help defend against fingerprinting. The <a href="http://dee.su/liberte-security">Liberte Linux</a> distribution is the only system I&rsquo;ve seen that automatically does this by forcing the screen resolution of 800x600.</li>
<li><strong>external monitors</strong>: If you are on a laptop, and have an external monitor around, it might be possible to have its resolution provide instead of your laptop screen. Note here that different operating systems handle this value in different ways. Some append the width and height of both screens to eachother.</li>
<li><strong>modifying the JavaScript engine</strong>: This solution has not been done very often and is considered a security risk, but there is a possibility that a new custom JavaScript engine could return a different value than your actual resolution.</li>
<li><strong>virtualization</strong>: If you are running your anonymous environment inside of a virtual machine, you can dynamically change the resolution very easily by resizing the window of the VM.</li>
</ul>


<p>There are different situations that heed different defense. If you run into a site you need access to that requires JavaScript, you&rsquo;re not going to be able to disable it. Same applies for the browser window trick if the service is detecting Screen.height as opposed to Window.height. Going into your screen settings and changing your screen resolution might work, but it&rsquo;s pretty cumbersome. The virtualization option is very plausible but requires that you are running virtualization software like Virtual Box.</p>

<h2>Real-World Attacks</h2>

<p>One example of software designed for fingerprinting is <a href="http://www.juniper.net/us/en/products-services/security/webapp-secure/">Juniper&rsquo;s Webapp Secure</a>. It is a tool that will fingerprint a web site&rsquo;s users based on a variety of metrics; one of which is your computer&rsquo;s resolution. By doing so, they are able to track their browsing experience across multiple sessions without any cookies.</p>

<h2>Applying to Registration</h2>

<p>Screen resolution is just a single attribute that can be keyed on but I find that it is relied upon the most often during web provider registration processes. This may be because the providers don&rsquo;t believe that anyone would go through the steps of changing their screen resolution &mdash; I&rsquo;m not sure. In any event, by merely changing your screen resolution, you are able to easily register without the stigma of anything you have done in a previous sessions possibly fingerprinting you. This along with clearing your cookies, connecting with a different IP address, and possibly manipulating the fonts that are installed on your computer will let you bypass the registration process&hellip;. sometimes.</p>

<h2>Conclusions</h2>

<p>If nothing else, I provide this as a reminder that your screen resolution is often a hard-coded, highly identifiable value you should actively defend against leaking to unknown parties. While not as identifying as say something like your MAC address, it remains a highly attributable value. Imagine a scenario where an adversary is correlating the online activity of someone visiting a site with a resolution of 1870x1300. Even if you&rsquo;ve securely erased your system before a forensic investigator has arrived, they will be able to easily notice that your laptop&rsquo;s screen resolution is 1870x1300. And because this resolution is highly unusual, it&rsquo;s a simple step to make the correlation between your laptop and its traffic.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journalist OPSEC Gap: Lessons From the Snowden Stories]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/05/16/greenwald/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/05/16/greenwald</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In Greenwald&rsquo;s book on Edward Snowden, <a href="http://us.macmillan.com/noplacetohide/GlennGreenwald">No Place To Hide</a>, he brings to light some of the details about how Snowden originally contacted him. The truth is, Glenn Greenwald slowed down the process of disclosing Snowden&rsquo;s secrets and it was only thanks to Laura Poitras that Snowden was considered as a legitimate source. This is an example of how old style journalism is falling behind the Wikileaks-generation of journalism. Alternatively, the two generations should be merging and learning from each other.</p>

<h2>Greenwald&rsquo;s Reluctant OPSEC</h2>

<p>The first chapter is written in a self-deprecating way &mdash; the same way that an old man would talk about computers to a young person; &ldquo;You kids and your computers.&rdquo; In this case, it was more &ldquo;You political dissidents and your cryptography.&rdquo; Even after repeated attempts by Snowden to have Greenwald merely install GPG, he could not be convinced.</p>

<blockquote><p>&#8220;Here am I,&#8221; he thought, &#8220;ready to risk my liberty, perhaps even my life, to hand this guy thousands of Top Secret documents from the nation&#8217;s most secretive agency &#8211; a leak that will produce dozens if not hundreds of huge journalistic scoops. And he can&#8217;t even be bothered to install an encryption program.&#8221;</p></blockquote>


<p>Greenwald admits that Snowden contacted him and repeatedly implored him to setup PGP for future communications and in response, Greenwald repeatedly procrastinated. Greenwald provided excuses that he was too busy and didn&rsquo;t believe this was a legitimate source due to the fact that Snowden wouldn&rsquo;t give him any more information. While the situation is understandable, it&rsquo;s infuriating to think about how the source was deemed not viable due to the fact that he was unwilling to transmit sensitive information securely.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://www.b3rn3d.com/images/greenwald.png" title="" ></p>

<p>The book goes on to highlight other times when Greenwald is having insecure communications over the phone and storing clear text versions of printed material in his bag. It was more than ten weeks between the time that Snowden tries to get Greenwald to install PGP, and the time he meets up with Poitras in New York.</p>

<h2>Laura</h2>

<p>Laura Poitras understood the implications of Snowden&rsquo;s information right away. In the first meeting with Greenwald about this subject, she told him to take the battery out of his phone (which he couldn&rsquo;t &ndash; iPhone). They switched tables two times at the restaurant to make sure no one heard them. She had not yet learned anything about the Snowden documents besides the implications that they were related to spying in some way. Because of this, she protected herself. Cheers to you Laura.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://www.b3rn3d.com/images/laurapoitras.jpg" title="" ></p>

<p>Laura Poitras is a film maker that is used to being targeted by government intelligence groups. Throughout her career, she has been stopped in airports, had her laptop confiscated, papers and documents stolen &mdash; all because of the places she&rsquo;s made films and people she has talked to. One example from Greenwald&rsquo;s book was an interview she did with Osama Bin Laden&rsquo;s driver.</p>

<p>Why does a filmmaker have better OPSEC than a journalist? It&rsquo;s not baffling, but it reflects the sad state of journalist awareness to operational security.</p>

<h2>Journalist OPSEC</h2>

<p>While frustrating, Greenwald is not an one-off situation. In fact, most journalists have no clue how to use encryption programs, or think about any kind of operational security logistics. This is the reason that sites like Wikileaks have become popular &mdash; they are on the cutting edge of technology, understand the value of providing an anonymous communication medium, and while they can&rsquo;t be regarded as having the same journalistic integrity as an institution like The Guardian, they are trusted (by some) to not accidentally or on purpose disclose their sources.</p>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='a cultural conflict between journalists that consider this type of software designed for &#8220;hackers&#8221; and tech savvy young people that are frustrated with the previous generation&#8217;s unwillingness to use technology.'>
At this point we have some tools designed to protect ourselves. <a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc1991">PGP</a> has been around for a millennium in Internet years. <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/strongbox/">Strongbox</a> is an attempt at securing communications between two people that don&rsquo;t know what they&rsquo;re doing. What have is a cultural conflict between journalists that consider this type of software designed for &ldquo;hackers&rdquo; and tech savvy young people that are frustrated with the previous generation&rsquo;s unwillingness to use technology. These &ldquo;hackers&rdquo; have spent collective years building tools and documents designed for these situations, and journalists aren&rsquo;t willing to use them.
</span></p>

<p>This technical knowledge gap will have to change and I believe that most journalists understand this fact. I don&rsquo;t know if there are American Journalist schools that teach them how be the next Glenn Greenwald, but they need to add a curriculum that covers technical OPSEC; PGP, proper communications, protecting your sources. They should be trained in the same way that the CIA runs a source. They should have dead drops, code words for whether everything is going as planned, designated meeting places, and unattributable communications.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Importance of Anonymous Email Addresses]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/05/16/email/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/05/16/email</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Email is dead, so why do we keep having to register for services using an email address? Think of a cloud service that doesn&rsquo;t use an email address as your identifier. Email has moved from being a communication tool, to an authentication system.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://www.b3rn3d.com/images/email.png" title="" ></p>

<p>Notice that we are not talking about anonymous communication here, because we know that email is the worst possible option for that at this point. We are talking about anonymously registering for an email account, so that you can also potentially register for other services anonymously.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s an example: Github. In order to create a github account, you need to give them an email address so that you can activate your account.</p>

<h2>The Problem</h2>

<p>The problem for anonymous privacy concerned peoples of the Internet, is that it&rsquo;s relatively difficult to get an email address while using something like Tor. Sites will block you in a variety of ways:</p>

<ol>
<li><strong>Blocking Registration</strong>: A site like Hotmail will block all access to register for a new address. You cannot use Tor to create an account.</li>
<li><strong>Blocking Service</strong>: The site will let you register, and subsequently block access to webmail from any Tor exit node.</li>
<li><strong>Requiring Extensive Validation</strong>: The site allows registration, and access, but will eventually require you to validate your identity through some kind of out-of-band system like an SMS.</li>
<li><strong>The Tease</strong>: And then there are sites that seem to allow you to register, access the service, but a few months down the line, you suddenly find out that your account has been blocked or requires a special non-Tor validation mechanism.</li>
</ol>


<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='the conclusion must be the same &#8211; these providers do not want anonymous users'>
In each of these cases, there are probably ways to evade these restrictions. For phone activation, we can use a <a href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/01/22/burnerphone/">burner phone</a>. In the case of registration just being blocked, you could probably find an un-attributable computer to borrow just for the registration process. But the conclusion must be the same &mdash; these providers do not want anonymous users. This is a network policy as much as it is a political statement. Because of this, even if you&rsquo;ve &ldquo;tricked&rdquo; the mail provider into allowing you to register, you should eventually expect to be blocked from access without notice. </span></p>

<h2>The Solutions</h2>

<p>So what options do anonymous users have? Remember, our goal is to eventually register for some other service that requires an email address, but we can&rsquo;t even register to get an email address in the first place.</p>

<h3>Webmail Providers</h3>

<p>Gmail, Yahoo, Microsoft, all offer webmail. In an ideal world, you could just register with them, get an email address, and be done with it. If your operation only requires that you hide behind a VPN, this may work for you but if you&rsquo;re using something like Tor, you are going to be blocked as described above.</p>

<p>Google has an interesting blocking program right now. When a user goes to register, they create a fingerprinted definition of that user &mdash; what is the resolution of their computer, what plugins do they have installed, what fonts are supported, etc. Therefore changing IP addresses and clearing out your cookies, will not affect the registation process. Google sets a number for each user so that when you first register for an account, you do not have to activate via SMS or phone call. But your third or fourth will require it. There is a method to the madness but I&rsquo;ve yet to figure it out (or care enough).</p>

<p>Yahoo is one of those situations where they allow anonymous registration, but after a month or two they will block access with an un-usable CAPTCHA. No mater how many times you attempt to complete it, when using Tor, the result will say that you have entered the CAPTCHA incorrectly.</p>

<p>This is a semi-plausible option, but generally not a good solution for long term operations. Its safe to say that I would almost never recommend using something like Gmail.</p>

<h3>Temporary Email Services</h3>

<p>Sites like Mailinator provide a temporary email address. You create a random address, sign up for a service using that address and you can check that mailbox whenever you need. Email is cleared out after a certain period of time. It&rsquo;s great for spam and sites with unnecessary registrations.</p>

<p>There are a couple of problems though. one is that many (most?) service providers block registration from Mailinator addresses. Another is that anyone that knows your mailinator email address, can access your email; the concern here being someone resetting your password.</p>

<p>Want an example? Why not reset the passwords for any of these Skype accounts:</p>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th></th>
<th> <strong>Name</strong>          </th>
<th> <strong>Mailinator Address</strong> </th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td> Merlin        </td>
<td> <a href="http://www.mailinator.com/inbox.jsp?to=merlin">merlin@mailinator.com</a> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td> anbu.mailinator   </td>
<td> <a href="http://www.mailinator.com/inbox.jsp?to=wert">anbu@mailinator.com</a> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td> wert          </td>
<td> <a href="http://www.mailinator.com/inbox.jsp?to=wert">wert@mailinator.com</a> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


<p>The point is, Mailinator works, when it works, but most of the time it doesn&rsquo;t. For short operations, or something you need temporary access to, this is a good solution.</p>

<p>Other alternatives to Mailinator:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.spambog.com/">Spambog.com</a></li>
<li><a href="http://maildrop.cc/">Maildrop.cc</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.guerrillamail.com/">Guerrilla Mail</a></li>
<li><a href="https://trashmail.com/">Trashmail</a></li>
<li><a href="http://10minutemail.com/10MinuteMail/index.html">10 Minute Mail</a></li>
</ul>


<h3>Acquired Accounts</h3>

<p>There are a variety of dark market sales that will give you pre-configured email addresses. These are either hacked accounts, or merely registered addresses to save you the hassle. You can buy them in packs of 100 or 1000 (and up) for a small fraction of Bitcoin. (It&rsquo;s not even worth linking to dark markets at this point but I&rsquo;m sure you&rsquo;ll find them.)</p>

<p>Purchasing email accounts from a dark market is relatively legitimate compared to the alternatives of breaking into the accounts yourself. If you have the time and effort, you might be surprised at how easy this is especially when you look at the very simple password reset questions often used.</p>

<h3>Self-Hosted Email</h3>

<p>One of the most suggested solutions to the email problem is to host email yourself. You purchase a domain anonymously using bitcoin, gift cards, or whatever anonymous method you choose. You spoof or falsify the WHOIS lookup information so that nothing points back to your real identity. Then you purchase a hosting provider using the same anonymous methods. Finally, you run a mail service so you can give yourself an infinite number of email addresses.</p>

<p>This is a viable solution for some operations. If you don&rsquo;t mind admin&#8217;ing a server and walking through the steps, this can be a good option.</p>

<p>The reason I don&rsquo;t like this is that it increases your attack surface. You are now hosting a mail server that directly points to you. If this server is exploited, every email address you have ever created is now accessible.</p>

<p>And for someone like me, that will compartmentalize identities, this solution doesn&rsquo;t scale. I would have to build out a new email server, new domain, new hosting provider for each identity. This is not a problem with the solution as much as it is a problem with OPSEC decisions.</p>

<h3>Trusted Anonymous Email</h3>

<p>The other option, is to find an email provider that you, yourself, trust. Trust is a difficult subject to cover so lets give it an operational definition of a service provider in which you believe won&rsquo;t sell your emails. (We&rsquo;ll ignore the possible nation state surveillance and potential legal jurisdiction issues.)</p>

<p>Here are a few providers that are &ldquo;trusted&rdquo; in many privacy circles:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://riseup.net/">Riseup.net</a>: This is a provider designed for activitists and community organizers. It is hosted in the U.S. In order to receive an email, you must know two people with an address, or try to request one from an admin on IRC.</li>
<li><a href="www.autistici.org/">Autustici</a>: Offer a range of services with privacy and activism in mind. Webmail, web site hosting, blog host, newsgroups.</li>
<li><a href="https://aktivix.org/">Aktivix</a>: Small site that offers free email addresses if you can convinve them you should have one&hellip;via email.</li>
</ul>


<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='the importance of a service provider that respects your privacy, compared to a provider in which you defend your privacy against'>
These are a breath of fresh air compared to the other solutions where you&rsquo;ve had to trick and lie your way into getting an account. These services generally approve of anonymous users and make it a goal to provide privacy-centric services. I can&rsquo;t highlight enough, the importance of a service provider that respects your privacy, compared to a provider in which you defend your privacy against.
</span></p>

<p>The problem is that these are often volunteer organized services, and community driven. That is to say, each of these providers have a hoop you need to jump through in order to obtain an address. This often means you have to befriend someone online, or give them a reason about how you are improving the world and need to maintain your anonymity.</p>

<h2>The Future</h2>

<p>The unfortunate truth is, email will be around for a long time. How long it will be around as an authentication system will hopefully be $longtime &ndash; n.</p>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='These federated services that were once used for social networking, are now becoming authentication endpoints'>
What&rsquo;s replacing email registrations is just as scary though. We now see &ldquo;Sign in with Google+&rdquo; and &ldquo;Login with your Facebook account.&rdquo; These federated services that were once used for social networking, are now becoming authentication endpoints. The future of an always-authenticated, always-attributed Internet is very close.
</span></p>

<h2>Conclusions</h2>

<p>This is the current state of email and anonymity from my point of view. Your operation dicates which solution is going to work the best, no single option will unilaterally work. For long operations greater than a year, it may be worth investing some time into a stable email address where self-hosting is the right answer. For operations that last for a month, temporary email address providers might be the right choice.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lessons Burned]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/05/10/back-and-reburned/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/05/10/back-and-reburned</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://www.b3rn3d.com/images/trainhop.jpg" title="" ></p>

<p>Three months ago I found myself at another impasse where you need decide to just let it all go and move on. My hosting provider &mdash; that up until that point had reliably allowed me to maintain my anonymity &mdash; suddenly requested that I verify my identity (for some random definition of identity in this case). There were a couple of ways to do this, and to be honest, it was something very easy to bypass. The point was that the provider suddenly did not enjoy my company.</p>

<p>What was interesting (see distressing) was this occurred synchronously with two of my email addresses being suddenly blocked requiring that I now log in through what they considered a &ldquo;trusted IP&rdquo;. These were two email accounts that had never, ever, touched eachother (never shared contacts, never same IP, randomized timezones). They were from the same provider which could possibly reflect a change in policy for everyone.</p>

<h2>Burn and Move</h2>

<p>Overly paranoid, long story, short, I wiped it all and moved on. In this case it was nice that they left my old site up for me to clone off. My assumption is that it will soon be taken down. And if they&rsquo;re reading this, they can feel free to do so. :)</p>

<h2>New Perspectives</h2>

<p>The set back was one of the first times that I honestly felt it was 100% necessary to burn and move on. Other times it wasn&rsquo;t mandatory but made sense at that point of the operation. Uncertainty is a decent motivator to review a few of my operational decisions. In the near future, I&rsquo;d like to share my current perspectives on:</p>

<ul>
<li>Email addresses</li>
<li>Hosting providers</li>
<li>Anonymous messaging</li>
</ul>


<p>These three are for many, the building blocks of all identities and extra care (which I thought I had given) should be taken. Until then, I&rsquo;ve imported my previous posts.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CIA Operative Teaches Spycraft and Psychology]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/03/09/cia-spycraft-psychology/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/03/09/cia-spycraft-psychology</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In two articles from Pursuit Magazine, Lindsay Moran, an Ex-CIA operative is
interviewed about being in the CIA, explains psychology around maintaing a
separate life, and gives a few cute stories about tradecraft. You can start
reading <a href="http://pursuitmag.com/lindsay-moran-former-cia-agent-talks-spycraft/">them</a> <a href="http://pursuitmag.com/lindsay-moran-former-cia-operative-why-became-spy/">here</a> if for nothing else, a fun read. I think there are some OPSEC
take-aways here in regard to psychological problems of maintaining
compartmentalized identities, using psychological motivators to exploit humans,
and defending yourself from surveillance &mdash; human or technical.</p>

<h2>Professional Liar</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;m most interested in the psychological perspective that she gives and
the issues that appear when one is compartmentalizing their identities. You
can&rsquo;t discuss, disclose, or share what&rsquo;s going on between your
various identities. In her case, she was maintaining just two identities; her
personal life, and her professional one. Having a career where everything you
do is regarded by the U.S. Government as Top-Secret and requiring a specific
clearance to discuss, is taxing on humans.</p>

<blockquote><p>â€¦I found that a lot of my relationships outside the Agency suffered. It becomes a chore to get together with people and have to lie to them because you feel guilty, and the result is that you kind of shut down, which is just not my nature.</p></blockquote>


<p>The natural tendency to &ldquo;shut down,&rdquo; as she says, is common in
groups that need to keep secrets; hackers, activists, military families.
You&rsquo;re maintaining an index of things you can share, and things you
can&rsquo;t. It requires discipline to keep track of these and adhere to the
lines. This is one of the problems with compartmentalizing multiple identities,
or even just one.</p>

<h2>Living in a Bubble</h2>

<p>Moran went on to describe, what I would call, a lonely sentiment when you are
working for the CIA.</p>

<blockquote><p>You tend to forget when you&#8217;re inside the CIA that there&#8217;s a whole other world out there. It&#8217;s to fall back on a cliche, a bubble.</p></blockquote>


<p>You&rsquo;ve lost track of reality &mdash; of your personal identity &mdash;
and you&rsquo;re more focused on maintaining your secrets and lies than having
personal relationships. I find this may hit close to some that have decided to
go dark and stay in the caverns of the Internet. For those, they may lean
towards the identity that gives them the most enjoyment, not the ones that
require the most work. You, for example, as a gun smuggler, trading on the
Internet, would much rather have a conversation with a fellow drug smuggler,
than your coworker at the bank. If for no other reason, you can speak more
freely about the topic without concern about accidentally leaking the fact that
you&rsquo;re smuggling guns.</p>

<h2>Exploiting Loneliness</h2>

<p>It should be noted that your adversaries realize that your life as a nomad is
lonely. It&rsquo;s a sad fact that many or most of the people caught doing
something illegal on the Internet are identified by LEO&rsquo;s that play into
how lonely your life is. Moran says:</p>

<blockquote><p>On the most basic level you&#8217;re acting &#8211;almost&#8211; as a clinical<br/>psychologist for your assets.</p></blockquote>


<p>She&rsquo;s referring to using the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Motives_for_spying">classic CIA definition of motivators</a>, and
exploiting these in people to get what she wants out of the asset. As a gun
smuggler, you may be motivated by ego, but there&rsquo;s no way you can brag
about how good you are at smuggling guns on the Internet. But when having a
private conversation with someone that appears to be a gun smuggler, why not
show off how cool you are.</p>

<h2>Anti-Surveillance Tactics</h2>

<p>One of the more benign, but subtly interesting comments that she gives was
referring to ways of evading surveillance. She contrasts how in the movies,
when someone it tailing you, you speed away as fast as you can. But in all
actuality, you are trying to lull them to sleep by acting boring.
There&rsquo;s a bit of HUMINT craft here, that can be applied to electronic
OPSEC. If you were under electronic surveillance, you can take actions to
protect yourself. The movie version, of speed away and run a red light would be
to choose to encrypt your communications. In actuality as a spy, nomad,
activist, or whatever, your first job is to not be directly targeted. Moran, in
her tailing example, says:</p>

<blockquote><p>You&#8217;re supposed to convince anyone following you that you&#8217;re not<br/>     a spy.</p></blockquote>


<p>We shouldn&rsquo;t speed away, we should walk into the grocery store or go to
the movies. This is where, in my opinion, our current common consensus with-
regard-to answering the question of &ldquo;How to defend ourselves against
electronic surveillance&rdquo; falls flat. Depending on your threat model, and
what you are concerned about, merely encrypting your communications is not
enough. By doing so, you have effectively confirmed, in the eyes of the
adversary, that you have something to hide and are therefore worthy of further
action. This tactic has been confirmed in an old Edward Snowden release that
states that the use of encryption, is a determiner of whether or not you will
be further targeted.</p>

<h2>Take-Aways</h2>

<p>This was a light, fluffy interview that I may be over-analyzing, but it does
highlight some ways in which the Americans view OPSEC. The psychology of the
subject has some direct take aways.</p>

<ul>
<li>When trying to compartmentalize, make
sure your motivators of money, ideology, coercion, and ego, and fulfilled
internally. Do not rely on an external resource for this.</li>
<li>A confidentiality and anonymity (or un-attributability) win over merely confidentiality in the
face of electronic surveillance.</li>
<li>Identify the natural tendencies to shut down, or tunnel yourself into a single identity, and compensate by building personal, trusted relationships in your other identities.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tor Country Codes]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/03/05/tor-country-codes/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/03/05/tor-country-codes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tor has the ability to let you choose which exit nodes you&rsquo;d like to use
&ndash; either by name, fingerprint, or country code. If you have a trusted
list of nodes you&rsquo;d like to use as a whitelist, you can use that, or if
you have a list of nodes on a blacklist, it supports that configuration. But
for those of us that are attempting to be someone else, specifically someone
from a different country, we can use Tor to not only hide our identity, but
make it appear to be from a specific geographic location.</p>

<p>Our example here may be an identity where you want to appear like a Ukrainian
dissident &mdash; when in reality you&rsquo;re a soccer Mom from Chicago, IL.
By setting up a dedicated machine, with a specific Tor configuration, you can
make sure that all of your traffic is routed out of an Ukrainian Exit Node.</p>

<h2>TORRC</h2>

<p>The configuration is simple, modify your torrc file to add the follwoing line
to ensure Tor will only use Ukraine based exit nodes:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>  ExitNodes {ua}
</span><span class='line'>  StrictNodes 1</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Please note that in all of these examples, we must enable StrictNodes. This
example will use either Ukraine, Uganda, South Korea, or Ireland as an exit:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>   ExitNodes {ua},{ug},{kp},{ie}</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<h2>Blacklisting</h2>

<p>You can also use this as a defensive measure as well. If you&rsquo;ve believe
there is some kind of geo-centric threat in Uganda, you can configure Tor to
never use these exit nodes.</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>   ExcludeExitNodes {ua}</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>You can exclude all node types for a specific country as well &ndash; exits,
relays, entry, and bridge nodes.</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>   ExcludeNodes {us}</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>You have the ability to whitelist all node types which is to say you can make
sure that your entire Tor circuit only uses a certain country. This is NOT
recommended of course. An ideal circuit will cross countries and legal
jurisdictions.</p>

<h2>The ?? Country</h2>

<p>Tor uses Maxmind&rsquo;s Geo-ip lookup system for this functionality. Some of
the versions of their database contain a &ldquo;??&rdquo; country code. This is
reserved for IPs they either don&rsquo;t know, or aren&rsquo;t willing to
share. (Tor is making some changes to compensate for this in the future.)</p>

<p>Knowing this can be useful in one of two ways. First, you may think that if you
don&rsquo;t know what country you&rsquo;re going to be using as a node, then
you don&rsquo;t want to use it. This is probably a legitimate thought without
having more information on what causes an IP to have &ldquo;??&rdquo;. Second,
and more interestingly, some (poorly configured) firewalls will automatically
drop connections from certain countries. Admins will say &ldquo;Screw it, block
China. Hacking problem solved!&rdquo; and ask for a raise. Maxmind is a very
popular Geo-ip lookup database and you can imagine that all of the security
services built into those fancy enterprise firewalls will most likely be using
it if it&rsquo;s doing geographic lookups. While many of these admins will have
policies for how to handle &ldquo;us&rdquo;, &ldquo;cn&rdquo;, and &ldquo;de&rdquo;, I&rsquo;ve found many have issues with a country code that is &ldquo;??&rdquo;. In one case, I&rsquo;ve found a system that blocks all exit
nodes, except those coming from a &ldquo;??&rdquo; country. I have not
identitied why this mis-configuration occurs, but hopefully someone can
leverage this to their advantage.</p>

<h2>List of country codes for Tor</h2>

<pre><code>Country                               Abbrev
ASCENSION ISLAND                      {ac}
AFGHANISTAN                           {af}
ALAND                                 {ax}
ALBANIA                               {al}
ALGERIA                               {dz}
ANDORRA                               {ad}
ANGOLA                                {ao}
ANGUILLA                              {ai}
ANTARCTICA                            {aq}
ANTIGUA AND BARBUDA                   {ag}
ARGENTINA REPUBLIC                    {ar}
ARMENIA                               {am}
ARUBA                                 {aw}
AUSTRALIA                             {au}
AUSTRIA                               {at}
AZERBAIJAN                            {az}
BAHAMAS                               {bs}
BAHRAIN                               {bh}
BANGLADESH                            {bd}
BARBADOS                              {bb}
BELARUS                               {by}
BELGIUM                               {be}
BELIZE                                {bz}
BENIN                                 {bj}
BERMUDA                               {bm}
BHUTAN                                {bt}
BOLIVIA                               {bo}
BOSNIA AND HERZEGOVINA                {ba}
BOTSWANA                              {bw}
BOUVET ISLAND                         {bv}
BRAZIL                                {br}
BRITISH INDIAN OCEAN TERR             {io}
BRITISH VIRGIN ISLANDS                {vg}
BRUNEI DARUSSALAM                     {bn}
BULGARIA                              {bg}
BURKINA FASO                          {bf}
BURUNDI                               {bi}
CAMBODIA                              {kh}
CAMEROON                              {cm}
CANADA                                {ca}
CAPE VERDE                            {cv}
CAYMAN ISLANDS                        {ky}
CENTRAL AFRICAN REPUBLIC              {cf}
CHAD                                  {td}
CHILE                                 {cl}
PEOPLE'S REPUBLIC OF CHINA            {cn}
CHRISTMAS ISLANDS                     {cx}
COCOS ISLANDS                         {cc}
COLOMBIA                              {co}
COMORAS                               {km}
CONGO                                 {cg}
CONGO (DEMOCRATIC REPUBLIC)           {cd}
COOK ISLANDS                          {ck}
COSTA RICA                            {cr}
COTE D IVOIRE                         {ci}
CROATIA                               {hr}
CUBA                                  {cu}
CYPRUS                                {cy}
CZECH REPUBLIC                        {cz}
DENMARK                               {dk}
DJIBOUTI                              {dj}
DOMINICA                              {dm}
DOMINICAN REPUBLIC                    {do}
EAST TIMOR                            {tp}
ECUADOR                               {ec}
EGYPT                                 {eg}
EL SALVADOR                           {sv}
EQUATORIAL GUINEA                     {gq}
ESTONIA                               {ee}
ETHIOPIA                              {et}
FALKLAND ISLANDS                      {fk}
FAROE ISLANDS                         {fo}
FIJI                                  {fj}
FINLAND                               {fi}
FRANCE                                {fr}
FRANCE METROPOLITAN                   {fx}
FRENCH GUIANA                         {gf}
FRENCH POLYNESIA                      {pf}
FRENCH SOUTHERN TERRITORIES           {tf}
GABON                                 {ga}
GAMBIA                                {gm}
GEORGIA                               {ge}
GERMANY                               {de}
GHANA                                 {gh}
GIBRALTER                             {gi}
GREECE                                {gr}
GREENLAND                             {gl}
GRENADA                               {gd}
GUADELOUPE                            {gp}
GUAM                                  {gu}
GUATEMALA                             {gt}
GUINEA                                {gn}
GUINEA-BISSAU                         {gw}
GUYANA                                {gy}
HAITI                                 {ht}
HEARD &amp;amp; MCDONALD ISLAND           {hm}
HONDURAS                              {hn}
HONG KONG                             {hk}
HUNGARY                               {hu}
ICELAND                               {is}
INDIA                                 {in}
INDONESIA                             {id}
IRAN, ISLAMIC REPUBLIC OF             {ir}
IRAQ                                  {iq}
IRELAND                               {ie}
ISLE OF MAN                           {im}
ISRAEL                                {il}
ITALY                                 {it}
JAMAICA                               {jm}
JAPAN                                 {jp}
JORDAN                                {jo}
KAZAKHSTAN                            {kz}
KENYA                                 {ke}
KIRIBATI                              {ki}
KOREA, DEM. PEOPLES REP OF            {kp}
KOREA, REPUBLIC OF                    {kr}
KUWAIT                                {kw}
KYRGYZSTAN                            {kg}
LAO PEOPLE'S DEM. REPUBLIC            {la}
LATVIA                                {lv}
LEBANON                               {lb}
LESOTHO                               {ls}
LIBERIA                               {lr}
LIBYAN ARAB JAMAHIRIYA                {ly}
LIECHTENSTEIN                         {li}
LITHUANIA                             {lt}
LUXEMBOURG                            {lu}
MACAO                                 {mo}
MACEDONIA                             {mk}
MADAGASCAR                            {mg}
MALAWI                                {mw}
MALAYSIA                              {my}
MALDIVES                              {mv}
MALI                                  {ml}
MALTA                                 {mt}
MARSHALL ISLANDS                      {mh}
MARTINIQUE                            {mq}
MAURITANIA                            {mr}
MAURITIUS                             {mu}
MAYOTTE                               {yt}
MEXICO                                {mx}
MICRONESIA                            {fm}
MOLDAVA REPUBLIC OF                   {md}
MONACO                                {mc}
MONGOLIA                              {mn}
MONTENEGRO                            {me}
MONTSERRAT                            {ms}
MOROCCO                               {ma}
MOZAMBIQUE                            {mz}
MYANMAR                               {mm}
NAMIBIA                               {na}
NAURU                                 {nr}
NEPAL                                 {np}
NETHERLANDS ANTILLES                  {an}
NETHERLANDS, THE                      {nl}
NEW CALEDONIA                         {nc}
NEW ZEALAND                           {nz}
NICARAGUA                             {ni}
NIGER                                 {ne}
NIGERIA                               {ng}
NIUE                                  {nu}
NORFOLK ISLAND                        {nf}
NORTHERN MARIANA ISLANDS              {mp}
NORWAY                                {no}
OMAN                                  {om}
PAKISTAN                              {pk}
PALAU                                 {pw}
PALESTINE                             {ps}
PANAMA                                {pa}
PAPUA NEW GUINEA                      {pg}
PARAGUAY                              {py}
PERU                                  {pe}
PHILIPPINES (REPUBLIC OF THE)         {ph}
PITCAIRN                              {pn}
POLAND                                {pl}
PORTUGAL                              {pt}
PUERTO RICO                           {pr}
QATAR                                 {qa}
REUNION                               {re}
ROMANIA                               {ro}
RUSSIAN FEDERATION                    {ru}
RWANDA                                {rw}
SAMOA                                 {ws}
SAN MARINO                            {sm}
SAO TOME/PRINCIPE                     {st}
SAUDI ARABIA                          {sa}
SCOTLAND                              {uk}
SENEGAL                               {sn}
SERBIA                                {rs}
SEYCHELLES                            {sc}
SIERRA LEONE                          {sl}
SINGAPORE                             {sg}
SLOVAKIA                              {sk}
SLOVENIA                              {si}
SOLOMON ISLANDS                       {sb}
SOMALIA                               {so}
SOMOA,GILBERT,ELLICE ISLANDS          {as}
SOUTH AFRICA                          {za}
SOUTH GEORGIA, SOUTH SANDWICH ISLANDS {gs}
SOVIET UNION                          {su}
SPAIN                                 {es}
SRI LANKA                             {lk}
ST. HELENA                            {sh}
ST. KITTS AND NEVIS                   {kn}
ST. LUCIA                             {lc}
ST. PIERRE AND MIQUELON               {pm}
ST. VINCENT &amp;amp; THE GRENADINES      {vc}
SUDAN                                 {sd}
SURINAME                              {sr}
SVALBARD AND JAN MAYEN                {sj}
SWAZILAND                             {sz}
SWEDEN                                {se}
SWITZERLAND                           {ch}
SYRIAN ARAB REPUBLIC                  {sy}
TAIWAN                                {tw}
TAJIKISTAN                            {tj}
TANZANIA, UNITED REPUBLIC OF          {tz}
THAILAND                              {th}
TOGO                                  {tg}
TOKELAU                               {tk}
TONGA                                 {to}
TRINIDAD AND TOBAGO                   {tt}
TUNISIA                               {tn}
TURKEY                                {tr}
TURKMENISTAN                          {tm}
TURKS AND CALCOS ISLANDS              {tc}
TUVALU                                {tv}
UGANDA                                {ug}
UKRAINE                               {ua}
UNITED ARAB EMIRATES                  {ae}
UNITED KINGDOM (no new registrations) {gb}
UNITED KINGDOM                        {uk}
UNITED STATES                         {us}
UNITED STATES MINOR OUTL.IS.          {um}
URUGUAY                               {uy}
UZBEKISTAN                            {uz}
VANUATU                               {vu}
VATICAN CITY STATE                    {va}
VENEZUELA                             {ve}
VIET NAM                              {vn}
VIRGIN ISLANDS (USA)                  {vi}
WALLIS AND FUTUNA ISLANDS             {wf}
WESTERN SAHARA                        {eh}
YEMEN                                 {ye}
ZAMBIA                                {zm}
ZIMBABWE                              {zw}
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Perspectives of OPSEC Models]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/02/17/perspectives-of-opsec/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/02/17/perspectives-of-opsec</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='operational security&#8217;s primary goal is to
mitigate risk while maintaining operational capabilities'>
As I&rsquo;ve discussed <a href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/01/10/ask-him-about-his-threat-model">before</a>, threat models or risk models help you to define the adversaries you should invest the most resources being concerned about. There are a variety of different risk perspectives you can use to design a
threat model: adversary-centric, asset-centric, or software-centric. We can
adopt these into very similar models for OPSEC plans. Each of these models have
a single principal that operational security&rsquo;s primary goal is to
mitigate risk while maintaining operational capabilities.
</span></p>

<h2>Adversary-Centric OPSEC</h2>

<p><img class="right" src="http://www.b3rn3d.com/images/adversary.png" title="" ></p>

<p>In these types of plans, we&rsquo;re focused on what an attacker or adversary
can do to us; who is coming after you, what they can do, and how you can
defend. An adversary-cetnric policy has the advantage of being much easier to
create and document because many people already think this way. It&rsquo;s very
simple to come up with a list of adversaries that have the potential to affect
what&rsquo;s important to you. The down-side of this approach is that you need
to know your adversaries. In the case of the NSA &ldquo;revelations&rdquo;,
many were shocked to find out that a nation-state had the type of capabilities
that were disclosed. Prior to this, not many were able to mitigate themselves
from these types of threats because they simply didn&rsquo;t know or fully
appreciate an adversary of this nature.</p>

<h2>Asset-Centric OPSEC</h2>

<p><img class="right" src="http://www.b3rn3d.com/images/asset.png" title="" ></p>

<p>This approach focuses on designging mitigations around your assets &mdash; the
things you value the most. If, for example, your asset is your ability to
privately communicate on the Internet, you&rsquo;re going to do everything you
can to ensure no-one can affect this. You&rsquo;re not focused on specific
adversaries per se in this approach, but you are doing everything in your power
to protect yourself. Maybe you&rsquo;re buying a VPN service or using a botnet
or Tor for all communications. Maybe you&rsquo;ve decided that you&rsquo;re
going to try out one of the new <a href="https://bitmessage.org/wiki/Main_Page">decentralized</a> <a href="http://dee.su/cables">messaging</a> <a href="https://crypto.cat/">systems</a> as a way of
keeping yourself secure.</p>

<p>One of the benefits of this method is that it&rsquo;s easy to explain why a
measure needs to take place. If you&rsquo;re operating in a group, this may be
an important factor. You can easily make the case that your asset needs to be
secure, therefore we are taking these steps to mitigate the risk. Contrary to
the adversary-centric approach, this is a less passive perspective &mdash; you
are not taking the point of view of being fearful of something happening, you
are merely performing the proactive, required procedures to keep your assets
safe.</p>

<h2>Operation-Centric OPSEC</h2>

<p><img class="right" src="http://www.b3rn3d.com/images/boxes.png" title="" >
This approach, my favorite, lends itself nicely to compartmentalization if
you&rsquo;re managing multiple identities across multiple operations. An
operation in this case could be an identitiy, a research project, an regular
activitiy or whatever, that may require specific operational security measures.
An operation-centreic OPSEC plan may sound recursive to you, but the gist is
that your plans are focused on your specific operation, and that operation
alone. The main difference between this and an asset-centric approach is that
it is designed to have drastically different and compartmentalized procedures
allowing for scalability without letting one operation interfere with another.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;ve ever taken a look at the security plans of a large, Fortune 500
company compared to that of a startup, it&rsquo;s quite possible that the
startup is able to implement simple, elegent, effective security plans while
the Fortune 500 spends millions of dollars designing a unilateral security
policy that severely inhibits the organizations operational capabilities. The
reason that a small, agile startup can devise elegant OPSEC measures, is the
same reason that compartmentalizing your OPSEC procedures in an operation-
centric point-of-view is effective.</p>

<p>The other reason that I like this is because it gives you a good balance of a
variety of different OPSEC approaches. You are paying attention to your
operation&rsquo;s assets while taking into account specific adversaries and
their attacks. As you define an operation &mdash; we&rsquo;ll say buying
illegal drugs on the internet &mdash; you will be scoped down to a specific
task and controlled environment. It lets you define boundaries in which your
OPSEC guidelines can define situations in which your measures/countermeasures
no longer protect you. This keeps risks at a minimum because you are only
defending against a subset of your activities &mdash; those associated with the
operation. In the example of buying illegal drugs on a darknet market, your
OPSEC guidelines can state that in the case of the darkmarket collapse (which
seems to happen regularly <a href="http://www.deepdotweb.com/2014/02/13/silk-road-2-hacked-bitcoins-stolen-unknown-amount/">lately</a>), your operation should fold and the identity
should be burned. You can take into accounts adversaries such as those that own
the market, and assets you&rsquo;re concerned about such as keeping yourself
out of jail.</p>

<p>I will admit, none of those listed are perfect, nor do they make up an
exhaustive list. They may however give you a starting point for building an
OPSEC plan for yourself.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[For Aaron]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/02/10/for-aaron/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/02/10/for-aaron</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://www.b3rn3d.com/images/aaronswartz.jpg" width="500"></p>

<p>I never had the chance to meet <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aaron_Swartz#Life_and_works">Aaron_Swartz</a>, but I have been lucky enough to
meet the people of whom&rsquo;s life he affected. <a href="https://thedaywefightback.org/">The Day We Fight Back</a> is a bitter sweet project to me, that helps commemorate Aaron&rsquo;s time on this
planet and the work that put towards improving the online society that we knew
and loved, as well as show the groundswell of community support.</p>

<p>I have no overwhelming feeling that TDWFB will have any direct affect on the
real issues that we are concerned about, but I believe it&rsquo;s important to
support this cause for many reasons. First of which is to show powers-that-be
that there is already a massive, soon-to-be organized community of people who
are willing to fight back for not just the way we interconnect between
computing devices, but for the community that has been created on-top of the
Internet. It&rsquo;s this community that we&rsquo;re hoping to rebuild either
through noble means of change, or on-top of the ashes of the previous
generation.</p>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='there are
people that operate in dark corners, not because of some kind of nefarious
activity they are performing online, but because this is the only legitimate
location where they can feel free to operate'>
I don&rsquo;t usually feel my personal opinions are appropriate for this blog,
but I think that there are a lot of people that have, similar to me, decided to
self-censor and remove their voice from the community. I believe there are
people that operate in dark corners, not because of some kind of nefarious
activity they are performing online, but because this is the only legitimate
location where they can feel free to operate&mdash; a feeling the online
community used to breed by default.
</span></p>

<p>Aaron believed strongly in the openness of information and sharing and
creativity and innovation &mdash; all the tenets of the online community that
we knew. He believed that these values should be upheld at all costs. In his
<a href="https://archive.org/stream/GuerillaOpenAccessManifesto/Goamjuly2008_djvu.txt">Guerilla Open Access Manifesto</a>, there&rsquo;s a quote that is salient beyond
just open access to information, but to privacy, surveillance, and anything
that degrades the online community:</p>

<blockquote><p>â€œI agree,â€ many say, â€œbut what can we do? The companies hold the<br/>copyrights, they make enormous amounts of money by charging for<br/>access, and itâ€™s perfectly legal&#8221; thereâ€™s nothing we can do to<br/>stop them.â€ But there is something we can, something thatâ€™s<br/>already being done: we can fight back.</p></blockquote>


<p>This is for Aaron; the days he fought, the fights of today, and the fights that
continue on his behalf.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Event Boundaries: Helping to Compartmentalize Your Operations]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/02/04/event-boundaries-helping-to-compartmentalize-your-operations/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/02/04/event-boundaries-helping-to-compartmentalize-your-operations</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I <a href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/01/13/braintricks-opsec/">wrote_previously</a> wrote previously about using your brain to help
compartmentalize you various identities. This is still a common thread of
research I&rsquo;m working on and wanted to further expand on the idea. The
short version of my previous post was that if you can create a completely
different operating environment for each of your operations/activities,
you&rsquo;ll be able to more easily maintain whatever OPSEC measures
you&rsquo;ve employed.</p>

<h2>Event Boundaries</h2>

<p>Event Boundaries is a theory that has come to my <a href="http://www.memory-key.com/blog/event-boundaries-and-working-memory-capacity">attention</a> recently. The
concept is simple &mdash; when you walk through a boundary such as a door,
gate, or different space, your brain automatically switches from its previous
mode of operation, to a new one. This is the reason that when you walk into a
room, you sometimes completely forget why you&rsquo;re there. The point to
focus on here is that the boundary defines a beginning and an end of an
environment.</p>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='When your brain knows there is a beginning and an end, studies show that this
helps to create a compartment for those memories.'>
When your brain knows there is a beginning and an end, studies show that this
helps to create a compartment for those memories. We can use this to our
advantage. In a perfect world, we could make physical barriers for each of our
identities so that when we switch to another operation, we switch operating
environments. Some realistic examples could be that Identity A always operates
in Starbucks coffee shops, while Identity B always operates in the local
library.
</span></p>

<h2>Logical Event Boundaries</h2>

<p>If you&rsquo;re confined to your own apartment, or have a static operating
environment, you&rsquo;re going to be left to tricking your brain into creating
logical event boundaries instead. One way to do this is to create an induction
procedure for that operation. Before you being working in that operating
environment, you must follow the same exact steps you&rsquo;ve done previously.
This should take into account as many senses as you can.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://www.b3rn3d.com/images/eventboundaries.png" title="" ></p>

<p>For example, you can create a video that is a compilation of various images; a
river, a mountain, an urban scene, and a zoo &mdash; it doesn&rsquo;t matter
the scense, but they need to all be in the same &ldquo;mood&rdquo; if you will
(ie. a gun fight is not the same mood as a running river). Specific sounds or
music are set in the background of the video. Whenever it&rsquo;s time to
assume that identity, you adjust the lights in the room to be very bright, you
put on your headphones, fire up that identities computer, and watch that video.
Following these steps, while you haven&rsquo;t physically entered a room, you
have logically created an event boundary that helps your brain to process and
recall that identity&rsquo;s operating environment.</p>

<p>When exiting, you must do something similar, but it cannot be the same process
as the way you entered. (Because you&rsquo;re creating the event of leaving the
room which has a much different feeling than entering.) Create a new video
consisting of a different mood and different music. I would suggest something
drastically different than your operating environment. If you normally work
quiet, create a loud video with lots of action. Finally, adjust the lights in
the room so that are at their previous state.</p>

<p>Even as I write this, I feel that this may seem over-the-top or ridiculous. I
might not disagree with over-the-top for what you&rsquo;re doing, but the
results are tangible. The point of all this is, if you work to maintain
multiple operations or multiple identities with different operating
requirements, this process can help (at least for me) to:</p>

<ul>
<li>compartmentalize each operation so that it does not interfere with your
personal life</li>
<li>maintain consistency for whatever OPSEC measures you employ</li>
<li>recall how that identity is supposed to act online</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tools to Evade Stylometrics]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/01/31/tools-styometrics/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/01/31/tools-styometrics</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Stylometrics is the idea that your writing style can be quantified, even
fingerprinted. The way you turn a phrase, the average word or sentence length,
the vocabulary used, all contribute to a a scientific perspective of your
writing style. In terms of OPSEC, stylometrics is an adversarial concern
&mdash; one of which can be difficult to defend against.</p>

<p>One of the operational security measures that Edward Snowden employed, was to
write short bits of information; small paragraphs, a few sentences, but never
long prose. This was, in part, because he had concerns that no matter what kind
of anyonymity systems or security tactics taken, if an adversary with enough
power was able to extract the plain text from one of his messages, it could be
correlated back to himself based on previous documents he had written.</p>

<blockquote><p>Snowden was not yet ready to tell me his name, but he said he was<br/>certain to be exposed &#8220;by his own hand or somebody else&#8217;s.&#8221;&#8221; Until<br/>then, he asked that I not quote him at length. He said semantic<br/>analysis, another of the NSA&#8217;s capabilities, would identify him by<br/>his patterns of language.</p></blockquote>


<p>Barton Gellman <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/code-name-verax-snowden-in-exchanges-with-post-reporter-made-clear-he-knew-risks/2013/06/09/c9a25b54-d14c-11e2-9f1a-1a7cdee20287_story.html">Washington Post Snowden Communications</a></p>

<p>Also to note, this is not merely an NSA capability, intelligence compaies like
Palantir posses this capabibility and wrap it into the products that they
offer.</p>

<p>In 2007, researchers for the <a href="http://readwrite.com/2008/02/14/spidering_the_dark_web">Univesity of Arizona</a>, scraped the Deep Web blogs,
forums, and anything else they could get their hands on, in an attempt to
attribute people. They crawled forums run by neo-nazis and devised a way of
taking all that information, and separating out who was who on the forums. They
used stylometrics to collect enough information to group people up based on a
variety of features.</p>

<h2>Types of stylometrics</h2>

<p>There are two ways in which stylometrics can be used against you. (Both of them
have their names borrowed from an approach to Natural Language Processing.) One
way, which is called &ldquo;Supervised,&rdquo; refers to taking a group of
documents with known authors, and attributing them to an unknown author. For
instance if we had a writing sample from Edward Snowden, we could attempt to
attribute his authoriship of something he anonymously posted, by comparing his
writing styles. This type is relatively easy for humans to do themselves.</p>

<p>The second type, &ldquo;Unsupervised,&rdquo; leverages computational power to
take a pile of anonymous blocks of text, and group them together based on the
writing style. The example, the neo-nazi forum research didn&rsquo;t identify
individuals posting to the forum, but they grouped which posts belonged to
NaziA and which posts belonged to NaziB.</p>

<h2>What makes up your style</h2>

<p>There are dozens of models that deliver a perspective on your writing style.
They&rsquo;ve been created by academics and all aim to be more accurate than
the next. One called the &ldquo;9 Feature Model&rdquo; is merely taking nine
properties like sentence length, unique words, a readability index, and some
other simple to measure features of the text to come out with a classification.</p>

<p>Other, more complex methods like the &ldquo;Writeprints&rdquo; method, use
hundreds of features to make their conclusions. I&rsquo;m simplifying this to
features classifiers, but these are actually extremely complicated models using
neaural nets to generate their results.</p>

<h2>Evasion tactics</h2>

<p>If we see this as a threat, we need to mitigate. Researchers who <a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/attachments/2019_28C3-authorship.pdf">presented at 28C3</a> define a few ways in which to evade being finterprinted:</p>

<ol>
<li> <strong>Obfuscation</strong>: Generally make the text appear unlike your normal writing
 style.</li>
<li> <strong>Imitation</strong>: Make your writing stile look like someone elses.</li>
</ol>


<p>(They also recommend what they call &ldquo;Translation&rdquo; which is merely
taking a text, using an automatic translator service to convert it to a
different language, and then change it back. I don&rsquo;t see any difference
between this and &ldquo;Obfuscation&rdquo; and it presents a new anonymity
issue.)</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://www.b3rn3d.com/images/style1.png" title="" ></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://www.b3rn3d.com/images/style2.png" title="" ></p>

<h2>Tool: Anonymouth</h2>

<p>These researchers even gave us some data that shows how effective each type of
mitigation is to defend against. They show us a break down of the stylometric
model employed, and how effective each type of evasion tactic was. They also
give us a tool to help us anonymize our own documents that works surprisingly
well. Althought it&rsquo;s very complicated.</p>

<p>There are a lot more details about how the tool works and when to use it, but
for now, you can take a look at <a href="https://github.com/psal/anonymouth">Anonymouth</a>. This is a Java tool that takes the document you&rsquo;d like to anonymize, compares it to other documents
you&rsquo;ve written, and then takes a variety of texts from other others to
compare against. The results give you a breakdown of common words you use,
attributing sentence structure, and even some suggestions about how to change
the document to defend against attribution.</p>

<p>As this is an Academic research tool, it&rsquo;s written in Java and awkward to
use, but in general, it is pretty effective. They are now working to automate
many of its features so that instead of manually anonymizing a document, you
can tell the tool a directory of documents that you&rsquo;d like to anonymize.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Burner Phone Best Practices]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/01/22/burnerphone/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/01/22/burnerphone</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There&rsquo;s a good mix of useful and mis-information in regard to burner
phones out there. I thought I would compile some facts and review the proper
use-case for a burner phone.</p>

<h2>Tracking: Fingerprinting</h2>

<p>Burner phones, for both CDMA (US Sprint, US Verizon Wireless) and GSM (Ever
other carrier network in the world), are easy to trace. Carriers specifically
segregate burner/prepaid traffic from normal subscriber traffic. Yes, this is
primarily used to control which type of traffic should receive priority, but
it&rsquo;s used by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Law_enforcement_officer">LEOs</a> to easily identify network traffic used by targets.</p>

<p>Bruce Schneier recently commented on what the NSA is actively doing in regards
to burner phones. In a recent lawsuit between the NSA and the EFF, the court
documents show that one of the ways the US keeps track of burner traffic, is by
fingerprinting the number of unique contacts, and the times of the calls. With
this information, it&rsquo;s much easier to keep track of whose phone is whose.</p>

<p>For example, Joe talks to John, George, and Jimmi on a daily basis. He cycles
through burner phones at least once a week. For each phone, Joe adds the
contact information for John, George, and Jimmi and calls only them. Joe stops
never re-uses a burner phone.</p>

<p>From this information, we can easily track his first burner&rsquo;s contact
(namely John, George, and Jimmi) because this information is <a href="http://www.forensicswiki.org/wiki/SIM_Cards">stored on the SIM</a>,
and correlate it to the contacts used by the next burner phone. How hard would
it be for law enforcment to trace this information? Turns out not very hard if
you&rsquo;re a subject of interest.</p>

<h2>Tracking: Location</h2>

<p>There are two parts to the location of your burner you need to be aware of.
First, carriers maintain logs of the signal strengh between your phone and a
carrier tower/base station. With this information they can <a href="http://www.al911.org/wireless/triangulation_location.htm">triangulate your location</a>. On your smart phone this is
considered your &ldquo;Course-Grain&rdquo; location as opposed to &ldquo;Fine-Grain&rdquo; that the GPS in your smartphone provides.</p>

<p>The second location to think about here is the location used to register/
activate the phone in the first place. For American burners, they are required
to call into a toll-free number and setup their new phone using a name,
address, and secret password. Of course this information is not verified and
can be easily spoofed. But the phone number used to activate the account, is
forever associated to that device.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://www.b3rn3d.com/images/phone.jpg" title="" ></p>

<h2>When not to use a burner</h2>

<ul>
<li><strong>hiding from a national adversary</strong>: If you think the government is after you,
there&rsquo;s really not much a burner phone is going to help you with. They
can pull up security camera bartage of when you purchased the phone, they can
map all the locations in which you&rsquo;ve powered on the device, they can
watch the calls being made by a variety of burners and correlate them all
together.</li>
<li><strong>near your home</strong>: Every time you power up, that information is logged. If you
decide to constantly turn on your device in or around our apartment, it is
very easy for even local law enforcement to find you</li>
<li><strong>calling someone you know that does not use a burner</strong>: If all you&rsquo;re
going to do is call Jimmy down the street, it&rsquo;s easy to correlate your
activities across multiple burners because the destination address never
change. It becomes a bit harder if Jimmy changes his phone number at the same
time you change yours.</li>
<li><strong>registering for a gmail address</strong>: you might think it&rsquo;s a good idea to
setup a burner to make a new email address but while it can be, you also have
to be careful with how you use that address, and where you registered your
phone. If you buy a phone in London, and then pretend that you&rsquo;re in
Brazil for all of your email correspondence, this will be a red flag for
investigators. Make sure you remember what that phone will be for.</li>
</ul>


<h2>When is a burner useful</h2>

<ul>
<li><strong>hiding from non-law enforcement</strong>: If your goal is to just make sure that no
one you know can find your name or home address, a burner is useful.</li>
<li><strong>registering for inconsequential accounts</strong>: If you just need to register an
account, but aren&rsquo;t concerned about being tracked back to its activity,
you can use a burner as an alternative to registering with a pay phone or
something else.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Pro tips</h2>

<p>Based on everything we&rsquo;ve discussed so far, here are some operational
suggestions. Feel free to suggest more that work for you:</p>

<ol>
<li> Get feature/dumb/flip-phones rather than smart phones. iOS, Android (or
 whatever other OS you choose) is not interested in keeping track of your
 privacy. Feature phones have the benefit of being generally too stupid to
 leak information about you.</li>
<li> Never turn your phone on in, or around your home. Take the battery out
 when it&rsquo;s not being used.</li>
<li> Leave your phone at a place you&rsquo;re going to use it to make sure it
 never gets turned on at your home</li>
<li> If possible, pay someone else to activate the phone for you. This is a way
 of removing yourself from the activation process completely. There are
 some burner trading sites on the deep web.</li>
<li> Fill your phone with fake contacts. Each burner should look like it has a
 different set of contacts in it.</li>
<li> Never save your real contacts in the phone. Put them on paper, or on a
 separate device, but never on the phone. This information is potentially
 saved on the SIM and accessible to carriers.</li>
<li> Pad operational calls with random calls. Dial numbers you don&rsquo;t
 know, leave messages, call tech support, send an SMS. Make it difficult to
 differentiate between your operations and random activities.</li>
<li> Use a burner as little as possible before switching to the next one.</li>
<li> If purchased from a retail store, wait at least 60 days to activate. This
 is usually how far back mom and pop stores keep security bartage.</li>
<li> Activate from a payphone as far away from home as possible, or at least in
 the area where you will be using it most often</li>
<li> Dispose of burner phones completely. Don&rsquo;t recycle them or throw
 them away in your apartment garbage. They should be destroyed completely,
 electronically wiped, and physically wipe down.</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Braintricks for OPSEC]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/01/13/braintricks-opsec/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/01/13/braintricks-opsec</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Creating different usernames is just the first step when we&rsquo;re developing an
OPSEC plan for pseudonymity. One of the most plausible threats to your privacy/anonymity/pseudonymity is one where the adversary correlates a personality
trait across all of your accounts.</p>

<p>In 2011, researchers from University of Cambridge published details in how to
correlate traffic patterns of a Tor user, to their real life identity. They did
this by taking advantage of the fact that most people visit a certain set of
websites on a regular basis. Reddit, Facebook, Twitter, or some specific site
of interest. This is an example where an attacker is taking advantage of a
personality quirk to attribute you to your identity.</p>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='SDM is when the
human brain compartmentalizes certain memories based on the state-of-mind of
that person'>
Your writing style is also something attributable. You may know that certain
adversaries have the ability to do correlation attacks on your writing style
(or at least Edward Snowden thinks so). Taking something that you&rsquo;ve written
anonymously and matching it to something you&rsquo;ve written in the clear.
The idea of State-Dependant Memory (SDM) can help us here. SDM is when the
human brain compartmentalizes certain memories based on the state-of-mind of
that person. While in that state-of-mind or consciousness, memories are harder
or easier to recall. Think of this like a lock box for your memories.  A common
example of this is studying for a test at a University. Before your exam, you
study in the room you&rsquo;ll be taking the test, at the time of day you&rsquo;ll be
taking the test, at the same desk that you will be using. When you go to take
your exam, your brain will flip into the state that you&rsquo;ve trained it for,
making it easier to recall those memories.
</span></p>

<p>You can apply this as a management tactic for you pseudonymity. For each
identity that is created, design a state of mind for that user. Your
consciousness can be adjusted using a combination of one of your human inputs:</p>

<ul>
<li>Music/Audio: play certain music, certain songs, certain albums or look into a
specific meditation album that can put you into a specific, reproducable
state of mind. (See Robert Monroe&rsquo;s tapes)</li>
<li>Environment: It might not be possible to switch keyboard, monitor, or desktop
environment you normally work under but changing where you work has a huge
impact. Find a public place that your identity always goes, or sit in a
specific area of your apartment.</li>
<li>Lighting/Colors: Studies have shown that lighting and the colors of that
light have a drastic impact on the mood and state of being. This could be as
simple as having a light on or off while working, changing the color scheme
of the monitor, or closing the blinds for a window.</li>
<li>Drugs/Chemicals: When trying to reach a state of mind, you&rsquo;d be hard
pressed to find a faster, more consistent way to get into a reproducible
state. Many stimulants like caffeine, Ridilin, and cocaine, have a common
affect on people where taking something like LSD may not give you
reproducible results.</li>
<li>Smells: As we&rsquo;re going through all the senses, don&rsquo;t forget smell. Simply
lighting a specific candle or type of incense can take you into the place
that you need to be.</li>
<li>Time: Being aware of the time of day and when the identity works, is not just
helpful to bring you to a specific state of consciousness, it can also help
deter adversaries from being able to tell what timezone you live in.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Did You Ask Him About His Threat Model]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/01/10/ask-him-about-his-threat-model/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/01/10/ask-him-about-his-threat-model</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Have you ever seen one of those arguments on forums or IRL where a group of
people argues which scenario is more secure compared to another? It goes
something like this:</p>

<blockquote><p>Hey, how secure is Cloud? Should I use that?&#8221;<br/> Alice: Cloud is fine. I just wouldn&#8217;t save your passwords in it.<br/> Bob: Actually, Cloud is really dangerous. If someone hacks into your<br/>account they&#8217;ll be able to get everything that you own in the<br/>Cloud.<br/> Carl. It&#8217;s worse than that! The cloud should never ever be used<br/>under any circumstance. It is inherently insecure.<br/> Doug: People that use the cloud should be removed from this earth.</p></blockquote>


<p>These are usually escalating arguments that try to pretend that if you have
some higher level of security measures in place, it&rsquo;s a sign of wisdom. The
truth is, every answer is wrong because they don&rsquo;t have enough information to
intelligently make a recommendation. What should have been asked is &ldquo;What
is your threat model?&rdquo; Or put simply, what are you legitimately concerned
about. A nation-state, hunting you down for disclosing its secret, or are you
just kind of concerned about your privacy without doing activities with life
ending repercussions?</p>

<p>You&rsquo;ve heard that IT guy tell you the story about how &ldquo;The most secure
computer is the one that&rsquo;s turned off, put in a locked room, and filled
with cement&rdquo; usually followed up by another IT guy adding in some other
obscene logistic. Yes this is secure, but it&rsquo;s not a real-world solution
because most computers have operational requirements.</p>

<p>Step away from technical examples &mdash; let&rsquo;s take the United States
Secret Service for instance. Their job is to protect the United States
President from a variety of adversaries. If your job was to protect the
President, why not just put him in a locked room padded with cement and keep
him there until the end of his term? Because he has operational requirements.
This is the rub of all operational security measures.</p>

<p>You can apply this to your lives. You shouldn&rsquo;t be asking how much you
care about security, you should be asking what is the biggest threat to your
well being. If you&rsquo;re just concerned about your privacy, but someone
attributing you to your activities results in embarrassment (as opposed to jail
time), then maybe your operational security measures can be more relaxed and
comfortable. They might even fit in with your current lifestyle.
If you&rsquo;re a nation state dissident and your activities being attributed
to you results in your death, your operational security measures are going to
be extremely high and would require a disciplined, rigid approach.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Managing Pseudonyms Better Than DPR]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/01/08/managing-pseudonyms/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/01/08/managing-pseudonyms</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When Dread Pirate Roberts was caught, there was a lot of talk about all of his
OPSEC failures. Specifically how he had used a pseudonym to reference another
pseudonym&rsquo;s email address, letting investigators tie together the
activities of both of those accounts.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve heard it time and time again that we need to
&ldquo;compartmentalize&rdquo; our lives and identities and never let them
touch. For most, this is easier said that done but here are a few thoughts on
making it easier.</p>

<h2>Start From Scratch</h2>

<p>When he started out, DPR probably didn&rsquo;t realize that his darkmarket
forum would take off as well as it did, and he probably didn&rsquo;t know he
was going to be such a juicy target for law enforcement. So he had made some
pseudonyms and was doing some research without paying much attention.
What we should learn is that, when it&rsquo;s time to go dark, there is no
looking back; we have to start from scratch. It doesn&rsquo;t matter how
popular you have become under one of your other nyms and how much community
&ldquo;cred&rdquo; you&rsquo;ve earned thus far, you have to drop it all.</p>

<p>Start from scratch and decide what you&rsquo;re doing. Make up new accounts,
and document your adversaries that you need to plan for. If you think you might
ever accidentally cross back over, burn those accounts. Generate new passwords
and forget them. Don&rsquo;t let yourself ever log into them again.</p>

<h2>Lose the Ego</h2>

<p>Starting from scratch also means accepting that, in some ways, you&rsquo;ve
completely wasted your time. The previous accounts you&rsquo;ve created can
never be used for what you other accounts are doing. You can send a private
message to your friends saying, &ldquo;Hey, this is actually
Th3D@rkDru1d&rdquo; because no matter how much you trust them, they will have
become a liability.</p>

<p>You can see this issue again coming into play with DPR. He writes about how he
is rich and powerful and feels limitless. It was his final power move of trying
to kill someone that actually took him down the hardest.</p>

<h2>Know Your Identity</h2>

<p>If you&rsquo;re creating more than one identity, you need to be able to know
that person inside and out. Names, addresses, background history, social
network, common websites. Even things like writing style and personality type.
All of these are tools that an adversary could use to correlate your accounts.</p>

<h2>Real Life is its Own Identity</h2>

<p>Your real life identity should be your most prized possession. It&rsquo;s the
most difficult one to burn, you can&rsquo;t just start from scratch, and most
do not want to cut ties with their personal relationships. So this is the one
you should protect the most.</p>

<p>One of the most common mistakes is tie your real life identity, to an online
pseudonym. It&rsquo;s becoming popular for &ldquo;hackers&rdquo; and
&ldquo;security researchers&rdquo; to share all their projects and information;
some of which is illegal. Technically, port scanning an un-owned host is
illegal but it&rsquo;s one of those accepted things like speeding. As
&ldquo;hackers&rdquo; are becoming famous at things like Defcon, Blackhat, and
any of the other thousands of security conferences, the reward for disclosing
things to the public is higher. This makes them make riskier decisions to get
that fame.</p>

<h2>Know Your OPSEC</h2>

<p>Decide on your OPSEC measures. Figure out what you&rsquo;re going to do to
protect yourself and your identities. Each of your risky online activities will
usually require its own separate OPSEC measures. Keep them divided, but keep
them consistent.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Defining Levels of Opsec to Your Identities]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/01/05/levels-of-opsec/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/01/05/levels-of-opsec</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you are compartmentalizing accounts, making multiple identities, and keeping
them separated, you run into a few problems. One of which is remembering the
OPSEC measures you&rsquo;ve decided to employ for each account.</p>

<ul>
<li>Political Dissident

<ul>
<li>Goal: Leak information about a local dirty politician</li>
<li>OPSEC: Work laptop but using a VPN service to access Twitter</li>
<li>Risks: Politician will come after you and your familiy</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Human Body Part Trafficer

<ul>
<li>Goal: Buy and sell kidneys, livers, and various body parts to the highest
bidder on the black market</li>
<li>OPSEC: Dedicated laptop running an anonymized OS. Do not access any other
services besides the black market forum. Never gets on the Clearnet.</li>
<li>Risks: Law enforcement may find you and throw you in jail for a long time</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>In each of these examples you have completely different activities and
completely different risks. The political dissident has decided she only needs
to minimally protect herself as the local politician she&rsquo;s messing with
doesn&rsquo;t have the means to figure out who would be leaking the
information. The body part trafficer though knows that he is a target and has
chosen to protect himself.</p>

<p>What happens when you scale even further: One identity runs a black market
forum, one identity likes to chat with people on twitter, one identity hangs
out in the Anon IRC channels. It&rsquo;s easy to lose track of which identities
are used for what and what kind of OPSEC measures you&rsquo;ve chosen to use.</p>

<p>ne solution to this is to categorize your identities into levels where each
level has its own decided upon OPSEC measure. For instance:</p>

<ul>
<li>Level 0 &mdash; No protections. You don&rsquo;t care about privacy and are
not concerned with other people attributing your online activities to
yourself.</li>
<li>Level 1 &mdash; Minimal: You are concerned about privacy, but choose simple,
minimalist tactics to protect yourself. For example, you are using a VPN
service for everyday browsing, but being caught is inconsequential.</li>
<li>Level 2 &mdash; Medium: You are concerned with your privacy and take action
to ensure that you are safe. It is likely that if someone finds out what you
are doing, you&rsquo;ll have to pay a price, but it is not a life-and-death
situation. For example, journalists working with a source use the TAILS
LiveCD.</li>
<li>Level 3 &mdash; High: Those users that are likely to be targeted, and likely
to have heavy consequences if caught. They have done everything in their
power to maintain their pseudonymity, but still try to lead some semblance of
a personal life.</li>
<li>Level 4 &mdash; Extreme: These are reserved for those people doing high risk
activities where the result of an adversary outing you is a matter of life
and death. You&rsquo;re prepared to forgo personal relationships, worldly
goods, and just about anything to maintain your anonymity.</li>
</ul>


<p>Knowing your likely threats, and defining your level of pseudonymity will help
keep management of your OPSEC measures consistent. Something that recent
arrests seem to have failed at.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
