<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[B3RN3D]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-03-09T11:08:43+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[b3rn3d]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Growing a Flower in the Dark]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2016/03/11/opsec-and-ego/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2016/03/11/opsec-and-ego</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.b3rn3d.com/images/dark_flower.jpg" width="200" title="Dark Flower" ></p>

<p>I like to use the metaphor of growing a flower to discuss the issues of OPSEC. It works on a couple of levels and I hope it can help delver my points. You can&rsquo;t use the same tools to grow a flower in the dark that you might normally: sunlight, access to water, fertilizer. You are human. You have needs. You need to eat, you need to sleep, you need to have a reason to do things that you do. Like the flower in the dark, our OPSEC may restrict our ability to feed our human needs.</p>

<p>Psychological human needs often get in the way of your operation.</p>

<ul>
<li>Loneliness</li>
<li>Self worth</li>
<li>Motivation</li>
</ul>


<p>The first step is recognizing that these are real, useful needs, and they should not be denied. Next we should figure out how to feed them. There are really two ways of looking at the situation to help you deal with them: Plan to ensure these feelings never happen or plan how to deal with these feelings <em>when</em> they happen.</p>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='feeding these needs may negatively impact your OPSEC policy, but not feeding these needs could have much more serious consequences.'>
I&rsquo;ll discuss some of the issues as well as some recommendations but as you&rsquo;ll see, my recommendations are in direct contrast to a good OPSEC plan. The first concession you need to make is that feeding these needs may negatively impact your OPSEC policy, but not feeding these needs could have much more serious consequences.
</span></p>

<h2>The Drought of Loneliness</h2>

<p>Depending on your OPSEC and operation, you are lonely. You sit in your cheap flat, with your secure computer, and nobody knows that you exist.</p>

<p>Let me feed my ego a little bit and disclose an anecdote. I&rsquo;ve spent weeks in locations not being able to communicate with anyone. If I am able to communicate, it is high latency and multiple days before a response. The lonleiness creeps in and as any tech savvy person in this decade does, they reach online for contact. A chat on IRC, darknet forums, whatever.</p>

<p>For me, the loneliness breeds different feelings; depression, laziness as well as a myopic focus on the task at hand. When you have nothing else to do, you go to work. Take care of the operation. Plan, review, and plan some more. There&rsquo;s nothing else to do.</p>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='you can’t be constantly watering your dark flower.'>
If your operation takes up a lot of your time, that&rsquo;s a good way of keeping your mind busy but if your plans have lots of periods of inactivity, and you must wait for things before you can continue; you can&rsquo;t be constantly watering your dark flower. This is when the lonliness creeps in and its best to recognize that this will happen and think of ways of fixing it.
</span></p>

<p>Here are some suggestions that work for me and hopefully you:</p>

<ul>
<li>Meet people in an agnostic setting such as a book club, pub, or sporting event. Be weary of topics and information that are discussed but if you need human interaction, this is a good way of doing it.</li>
<li>Find an out-of-band low latency communication network. Connect to IRC or Twitter from an Internet cafe. Ensure you&rsquo;ve compartmentalized everything properly and you&rsquo;re not using the same network connection as your main operation, but if you need to talk to someone.</li>
<li>Make a friend. Yes this sounds simple or scary depending on the person but meeting a friend or partner you can confide in helps a lot. They might not be able to come over and visit you and you might seem like you&rsquo;re a very private person to them, but sometimes having a short conversation about the weather is all you need to remind you that you&rsquo;re connected to the rest of the world.</li>
<li>Attend a public event. I&rsquo;ve found that even if I&rsquo;m not interacting with people, being a fly on the wall at a very large event makes me feel less lonely. Even a bit of eye contact helps make you feel better.</li>
<li>Phone hotlines. I&rsquo;ll be honest, I&rsquo;ve never done this but a friend suggested it and swears by it. They suggested a suicide hotline but I feel that&rsquo;s a bit crazy especially as these services are designed to track your location. Phone sex services are usually expensive too. If you can find some kind of free hotline service that lets you use your burner phone, maybe this is something for you.</li>
</ul>


<h2>The Sunlight of Self Worth</h2>

<p>We know that <a href="blog/2015/02/04/ego-and-opsec/">your ego can get in the way of your OPSEC</a> and all you can do is recognize that, be as disciplined as possible, compensate for what&rsquo;s missing, and continue on. Your self worth is an inner conversation that defines you as a person. What are you good at? What are your best traits? Do you have a place in the world where you can deliver these skills?</p>

<p>You&rsquo;ve likely met someone that has an inflated sense of self worth. They&rsquo;re pompous about every thing they do and they aren&rsquo;t afraid of sharing it. Understand that these people are trying to feed their self worth and the more obnoxious they seem, the more starving they are for external validation. It may not need to be said, but your OPSEC may deter you from being one of these types.</p>

<p>As your flower tries to grow in the shade, it will miss the warmth of the sun. You can&rsquo;t just show off your operations in the light of the day or on a clearnet site. You can&rsquo;t post on Reddit and read through the comments]to see if people like you.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/onions/comments/28tpxg/liberte_tor_distro_forces_screen_resolution/">Maybe you can</a>. But let me say that in my experience, if you start questioning the value of your operation or your own personal self worth, you will start making concessions about what you&rsquo;re willing to do or share to try and feed it. You&rsquo;ll start thinking about chatting about it on IRC or Twitter and looking for something. Understand that searching for external validation is normal but make sure you stay vigilant about your OPSEC.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s hard to provide generalized recommendations for you. This is a question about your own personal feelings, motivation, and operation. Here&rsquo;s again, IMHO, some things you can try:</p>

<ul>
<li>Make a blog! A bit tongue-in-cheek but if I&rsquo;m honest, the entire purpose of this blog is to help me stay vigilant with my operations. The positive feedback is what keeps this going and at least makes me feel like I&rsquo;m useful. I am in fact at this moment, attempting to feed my self worth. :)</li>
<li>Meet like-minded peers. The term &ldquo;community&rdquo; is often nothing more than a circle of like-minded people aimed at validating each others' sense of worth. Join a community. Find people that do what you do and make some responsible disclosures while maintaining your pseudonymity.</li>
<li>Share your results with the world. If you have an operation with an output that could improve the world, share it. Watch how good it feels to see that other people appreciate the effort you&rsquo;ve put in.</li>
<li>Be honest about your operation and if you really have come to the conclusion that it&rsquo;s not worth your effort, shut it down. Do so in a controlled way.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Feeding Your Motivation</h2>

<p>Don&rsquo;t underestimate the need for motivation. At the beginning of your operation you will be very motivated. You&rsquo;ll have goals and aspirations and you&rsquo;ll be truly excited to accomplish your tasks. Without proper maintenance, these feelings fade.</p>

<p>In the best case, the result is that the operation expires. You don&rsquo;t continue. It atrophies and you let it die but there are no real risks in you doing this. Some operations aren&rsquo;t as lucky. If you don&rsquo;t maintain the operation or shut it down cleanly, you put yourself at risk. What happens if someone finds out your ran the operation years later? Is there anything that might identify you?</p>

<p>Motivation is what feeds your dark flower. Without enough motivation, you will simply not grow, become stale, and eventually wilt away. How can we stay motivated:</p>

<ul>
<li>Start an operation, and write down exactly why you are doing this in the most detail possible. Yes this is a risky proposition but if you can keep it secure, it can serve as an affirmation on the days when you&rsquo;re questioning whether you should be doing what you do.</li>
<li>If your operation is related to some moral or ethical motivation, review the reasons you chose to do this. Read articles and papers about what made you want to do this in the first place. If you&rsquo;re a hactivist, remind yourself of the bad things and why you&rsquo;re trying to be on the good side.</li>
<li>Limit outside influence. In contrast to the last suggestion, don&rsquo;t read anything. Don&rsquo;t let articles, comments, or TV shows suck out your motivation.</li>
</ul>


<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='spend a few hours thinking about the meat bag that’s actually running your operation.'>
If you think all of these suggestions and discussion does not apply to you, let us at least agree that our physical and psychological needs are paramount. If you&rsquo;ve spent hours on securing your laptop, network connection, and built an OPSEC policy, spend a few hours thinking about the meat bag that&rsquo;s actually running your operation. I hope that this serves as a reminder to not only plan for the technical details, but also find ways to grow your flower in the dark.
</span></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mass Surveillance for the Masses]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2016/03/05/pratical-opsec/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2016/03/05/pratical-opsec</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.b3rn3d.com/images/nypd_camera.jpg" title="NYPD Camera" ></p>

<p>I really like learning about new OPSEC tactics, especially if they&rsquo;re done
by the non-tech savvy. Below we talk about the threat model of a Harlem
residents and their defensive tactics.</p>

<h2>Harlem: Surveillance Hipsters</h2>

<p>New York City&rsquo;s, Harlem, is home to the city&rsquo;s lower income population. Not
impoverish but, not Manhattan. Harlem has had an illustrious history being
targeted by NYPD and other forms of law enforcement. Surveillance is part of
every-day life. Who better to give us some perspective on dealing with mass
surveillance on a day-to-day basis.</p>

<p>Harlem residents aren&rsquo;t concerned about NSA or GCHQ. They have a local
surveillance issues to deal with:</p>

<ul>
<li>Surveillance from their employers who install cameras to watch them work.</li>
<li>Surveillance from the local NYPD who have installed street cameras on the
corners that they know are not installed in Manhattan.</li>
<li>Surveillance from ex-boyfriends on Facebook who are keeping track of who
they talk with or what parties they go to.</li>
</ul>


<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='You
might not find their tactics useful, but it serves as a remember that
OPSEC is dependent on the threat model.'>
They have a different threat model compared to the nation-state dissident. You
might not find their tactics useful, but it serves as a remember that
OPSEC is dependent on the threat model. Someone hiding from the government
employs different tactics than someone hiding from their ex-boyfriend. The
threats are one in the same.
</span></p>

<h2>Family Plan Surveillance</h2>

<p>The US has &ldquo;Family Plans.&rdquo; These are cell
phone plans that you share with trusted friends and family to
can keep your bill to a minimum. But what happens when you no longer trust
someone on the plan? You don&rsquo;t kick them off. You ignore them. It&rsquo;s cheaper.</p>

<p>For some of these sketchy carriers, a member of the plan can:</p>

<ul>
<li>Get access to a backup of the phone&rsquo;s contact lists</li>
<li>Read text messages</li>
<li>Get the call records for the account</li>
<li>Track the location of a phone using a &ldquo;Find My Phone&rdquo; app</li>
</ul>


<p>This is their threat. On a day-to-day basis they aren&rsquo;t worried about the FBI
cracking down on them, they&rsquo;re worried about their ex-boyfriend stalking them.</p>

<h2>Social Lions</h2>

<p>We know that LEO&rsquo;s will keep track of social networking in their jurisdiction.
NYPD has invested millions to keep track of this effort. This is done in one
of a few ways. Most common of which, NYPD will make a request to Facebook for
access to a specific facebook account. I&rsquo;m told that 80%-90% of the time,
Facebook does not contest these requests and as long as it&rsquo;s coming from an
attributable law enforcement office, they&rsquo;re provided without any oversight.</p>

<p>The other more nefarious <a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/12/10/7341077/nypd-harlem-crews-social-media-rikers-prison">tactic that NYPD specifically uses</a> is to generate
fake accounts and target individuals in the neighbor hood. Keep track of their
friends, watch what parties they go to, see what people are talking about.</p>

<p>The people in these neighborhoods know this is happening in the same way that
they know the street cameras in the streets are keeping track of them.</p>

<h2>Harlem OPSEC</h2>

<p>For the non-tech savvy, their tactics are brilliant. They include:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Emoji-contacts</strong>: Never saving their friends names in their phone. Use emoticons instead. Smiley
face is a new boyfriend. Cake is your friend from the club. Happy penguin is
your pot dealer.</li>
<li><strong>Never using iPhones</strong>: They don&rsquo;t trust these devices and their tracking
capabilities. Instead use a cheap Android device they feel can&rsquo;t track them
as accurately.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t use SMS</strong>: Use messaging apps like snapchat for messages with new boyfriends. They know
that these are protected and don&rsquo;t show up on the records for the account.</li>
<li><strong>Watch Out Who Friends You</strong>: They believe that the NYPD is &ldquo;Cat Fishing&rdquo;
them to learn about their social circles and keep track of things they post
that might be illegal.</li>
</ul>


<p>Look, these aren&rsquo;t tactics that a tech-savvy person would use, but they show
real-world examples of different kinds of threats and ways to compensate for them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using a VPN With Tor]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2016/02/08/vpn-and-tor/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2016/02/08/vpn-and-tor</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://www.b3rn3d.com/images/torvpnsilly.png"></p>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='Should I use Tor to VPN into a VPN to connect to Tor via VPN… with Tor.'>
The question comes up semi-regularly: &ldquo;Should I use a VPN to connect to Tor?&rdquo; and &ldquo;Should I use Tor to connect to a VPN?&rdquo; and various combinations of Should I use Tor to VPN into a VPN to connect to Tor via VPN&hellip; with Tor.
</span></p>

<p>The developers at the Tor Project (whom I respect immensely and believe know what they&rsquo;re talking about) have a unilateral policy for this to never use a VPN to connect to Tor. Here&rsquo;s a snippet from a recent discussion on the <a href="http://archives.seul.org/tor/talk/">tor-talk mailing list</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>...if somebody somehow breaks the anonymity of your Tor<br/>circuit, it's nice to have another layer behind that. But if somebody guesses that you're using a particular VPN, or you pick a VPN that they're already monitoring for other reasons, then you basically let them see the beginning of your circuit when otherwise they might not have been able to.</p><footer><strong>Roger Dingledine</strong> <cite><a href='http://archives.seul.org/tor/talk/Jan-2016/msg00225.html'>Tor-talk</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>In this he&rsquo;s saying if you&rsquo;re using a VPN to connect to Tor, you&rsquo;re putting yourself at greater risk because the VPN service has a log of your information, your connection times, and the fact that you made a connection to Tor. This is supposed to be higher risk because if a nation state decided to perform passive monitoring, the place they would start is the VPNs. (He also compares this to having a consistent first hop guard node that everyone uses but I&rsquo;ll leave that debate for another day.)</p>

<h2>He&rsquo;s Right&hellip; Sometimes</h2>

<p>Dingledine&rsquo;s logic is sound and if one were to have a policy to share with a community, it should be this one because it puts the least amount of risk on tor users. But, as with most things related to security, a unilateral policy is not always the best one. You need to know your <a href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/01/10/ask-him-about-his-threat-model/">threat model</a>.</p>

<h2>The Case of the Harvard Bomber</h2>

<p>There is a now <a href="http://edition.cnn.com/2013/12/17/justice/massachusetts-harvard-hoax/">famous case of student at Harvard</a> who had not finished studying for his finals and decided he wanted to email a bomb threat into the school to stop tests from happening. He went back to his dorm room, fired up Tor Browser, and sent an email from Guerrilla Mail to the school.</p>

<p><img class="right" src="http://www.b3rn3d.com/images/eldo.png"></p>

<p>In this case, tor protected his anonymity. The email could not be traced back through the Tor network and to his IP address. Tor did it&rsquo;s job. His downfall was that he made the connect to Tor from his dorm room. The university admins simply went back and found all the tor connections at the time of the email, and found that it was a very small segment of students. The police went to each of those students and eventually found their man.</p>

<p>What if the Harvard Bomber used a VPN to first connect into Tor? Would it have saved him? Maybe, or at least it would have made it more difficult. He would connect into the VPN service used by hundreds or thousands of other people, and then connect into the Tor Network. This might mean that even when they noticed the Tor traffic, they wouldn&rsquo;t be able to attribute it to a specific student because there would be no log of them connecting to the Tor network. (That being said, Harvard could subpoena the VPN provider and try to determine which of the VPN users were from Harvard and which of them connected through Tor but I&rsquo;m trying to make a point. :) )</p>

<h2>When to VPN > Tor</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://www.b3rn3d.com/images/vpntor.png" title="VPN > Tor" ></p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s when you <em>might</em> want to use a VPN to connect into Tor:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Geographic fingerprinting</strong>: You are from a small village with not very many Tor users. If there was a suggestion that sketchy activity has happened, they would knock on your door first. Especially if your operation was geographically specific (like a bomb threat).</li>
<li><strong>Untrusted ISP</strong>: You know that your ISP is monitoring, logging, and sharing your connection information (hint: they are). You could make a choice to hide your connection details from your ISP and instead give that responsibility to your VPN service which you have more trust for.</li>
<li><strong>Plausible Deniability</strong>: You could rely on the fact that thousands of other people are using the VPN service at that same time so it&rsquo;s difficult to correlate activities to an individual.</li>
<li><strong>Jurisdiction Diversity</strong>: It&rsquo;s easy for most organizations to issue a subpoena to a company in their same company. It&rsquo;s also easy for any of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Five_Eyes">5, 9, or 14 Eyes</a> to target services in their shared jurisdictions. If you have a VPN provider that is not in one of these jurisdictions, you can use them to make it harder to issue subpoenas to.</li>
</ul>


<h2>When to Tor > VPN</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://www.b3rn3d.com/images/torvpn.png" title="Tor > VPN" ></p>

<p>This is a bit more difficult to accomplish but possible. The issues here are you have to make sure you&rsquo;ve purchased a VPN service anonymously, make sure that it allows connections via tor, and make sure it supports TCP as tor is a TCP-only protocol. The only scenario I can think of that you would need this is:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Tor Blocked</strong>: Less of a security issue and more about usability, if a service blocks all tor exit nodes, you can try to use tor to hide you connection into a VPN service which is unlikely blocked.</li>
</ul>


<p>That being said, this is a really bad idea because when you have a consistent endpoint you connect to, it could have unknown consequences to your anonymity. This is the main reason that Tor switches circuits regularly instead of using the same circuit every time.</p>

<h2>When to VPN > Tor > VPN or Tor > Tor</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://www.b3rn3d.com/images/vpntorvpn.png" title="VPN > Tor > VPN" ></p>

<p>Now we&rsquo;re getting nutty but we can think it through. You&rsquo;ve made the choice to connect to tor via VPN, why not make another hop and just connect to another VPN service via Tor. Or, if you think 1x tor is pretty good, so 2x tor must be even better! Use cases:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>You&rsquo;re nutty:</strong> Generally if you think there is an undisclosed vulnerability in tor, that is actively being used, but you still think that tor is the best option, you want to protect yourself by layering methods on top of tor.</li>
</ul>


<p>Whatever your rationality, know that this method has not been tested to see if it maintains your anonymity. There are so many edge cases of mis-configuration, fingerprinting attacks on the service, and plausible statistical attacks on your connection, you shouldn&rsquo;t assume this makes any sense.</p>

<h2>Further Reading</h2>

<p>VPN&rsquo;s are just one example of laying protections on top of tor. You could us private VPN hosted on a VPS, or SSH service, or if don&rsquo;t understand any of this, a proxy. This debate comes up so regularly that lots of groups have posts and wiki pages about it. Check out the links below for additional information:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/doc/TorPlusVPN">https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/doc/TorPlusVPN</a></li>
<li><a href="https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-talk/2012-January/022916.html">https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-talk/2012-January/022916.html</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Worst That Could Happen: Substantiating Their Fears]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2016/02/02/the-worst-that-could-happen/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2016/02/02/the-worst-that-could-happen</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the latest Snowden document released is hilariously named: <a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/2699620/What-Is-the-Worst-That-Can-Happen-March-2010.txt">What&rsquo;s The Worst That Could Happen</a>. In effect, this is the Government&rsquo;s thought process involved in determining the risk associated in launching a targeted attack on someon. In theory, this served as a guide to remind UK spooks of the various risks that are involved when trying to exploit someone. (It reads like it was put together by some GCHQ intern so I would pay too much attention to it.)</p>

<p>One of your main goals of your OPSEC plan is to reduce the likeliness of attack. With this document, we can see what an attacker believes to be the risks or their fears, and exploit them. As with all operation decisions, the risks outweigh their rewards. So let&rsquo;s make it risky for them to target you.</p>

<h2>Fears of Discovery</h2>

<p>Most of the document makes up a list of various different <em>results</em> of being discovered like if I catch someone in my bed room, the result would be that I could identify the person and punch them in the face. But the discovery section is where it gets interesting. This is a list of all the various ways they&rsquo;re concerned about being discovered. Their job, prior to deciding if an operation should be launched, is to identify the risk of your discovering them. Lets substantiate their fears by building some OPSEC plans.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the list:</p>

<ul>
<li>Compromise of operation during installation</li>
<li>Inadequate personnel security controls and subsequent information leak</li>
<li>Discover of installed hardware (including post-operation)</li>
<li>Forensic discovery of installed software</li>
<li>Discovery of a suspicious audit trail/logs/registry</li>
<li>Discovery of suspicious RF energy</li>
<li>Suspicious profile caused by hardware/software malfunction</li>
<li>Discovery of egressed traffic</li>
<li>Discovery through other IT leakage</li>
<li>Vulnerability to HIS or other monitoring</li>
<li>Inadequate monitoring of profile generated by operation</li>
<li>Inadequate review of risks during the lifetime of the operation</li>
<li>Reliance on an uncertain supply chain or other risky dependencies</li>
<li>Failure by operators to cover tracks, including clearing logs/changing read statusof emails</li>
<li>Novel capabilities and techniques having unknown effects outside of lab testing conditions</li>
<li>Unforeseen changes to hardware or software leading to compromise of techniques or installation</li>
<li>Hardware/software malfunctions leading change in target behaviour, potentially including forensic investigation (and potential discovery) and/or loss of target access</li>
</ul>


<h2>Compromise During Installation</h2>

<p>A relatively easy fear to substantiate is the detetion of an exploit device installation. This could be an application or hardware installation a device you own as well as physical security threats like microphones or cameras. Suggestions might be:</p>

<ul>
<li>Security cameras to monitor your workspace.</li>
<li>Custom log that detects when unknown USB devices are installed.</li>
<li>Tools like tripwire that detect modifications to your OS and prevent installation.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Catching Them In The Act</h2>

<p>This  refers to catching a person in the middle of their operation. Examples would be sketchy vans parked outside of your flat, cars tailing you over long distances, or people following you on the streets. There are some fun OPSEC tactics we can apply here:</p>

<ul>
<li>Take illogical paths (circle around the block).</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t have a predictable pattern of activities.</li>
<li>Use security cameras to keep a log of people around your</li>
</ul>


<h2>RF Detection</h2>

<p>Some of the &ldquo;bugs&rdquo; used by these types of people communicate by radio frequency. If you can show that you know about radio and that you know how to detect signals being relayed, you make yourself a risk of catching them.</p>

<ul>
<li>Use a software defined radio (<a href="https://greatscottgadgets.com/hackrf/">HackRF</a> or <a href="https://nuand.com/">BladeRF</a>#) to monitor normal radio signals around your facility. Regularly monitor for changes and send alerts.</li>
<li>Use bug detection tools (usually pretty expensive) to sweep your living space.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Malfunctions and Crashes</h2>

<p>The NSA&rsquo;s TAO program has a variety zero-days at their disposal. Most often, these exploits will cause some kind of crash on your system. When a crash happens, don&rsquo;t react by saying &ldquo;Oh, it does that sometimes.&rdquo; Make sure you have a way of detecting crashes and logging them somewhere to determine what occurred.</p>

<ul>
<li>Review all your logs after a crash. This seems simple but if you don&rsquo;t have time to debug a crash, at least store them for review later</li>
<li>Use tools like <a href="http://www.mcelog.org/">mce-log</a> that not only keep logs of hardware events but help predict when a crash is going to occur again.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Exfiltration Detection</h2>

<p>If something is installed on one of your devices, it alone can only collect information. Eventually it will need to exfiltrate it back to the attacker. There are some simple things you can do to try and detect when unauthorized connections are being made on your network.</p>

<ul>
<li>Use strict egress filtering on your operation&rsquo;s network segment. Only allow access to hosts you trust, via protocols you expect, over ports you know.</li>
<li>Alert yourself on unexpected network traffic such as outbound connections to other countries.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Missing From The List</h2>

<p>The list of course is not exhaustive. They don&rsquo;t go very deep into the various different discovery tactics. For example, you may consider building an extremely public system that everyone knows about and likes. In the case that something is attacked or exploited, a canary could go off that destroys that service. This would be the idea of collateral damage which could affect their public perception, share what country originated the attack, or just causes some political turmoil which makes it not worth the effort. In some ways, Edward Snowden can be an example of this.</p>

<h2>Conclusions</h2>

<p>Don&rsquo;t forget, each of these examples isn&rsquo;t talking about what you do <em>after</em> you&rsquo;ve been targeted, it&rsquo;s about a show of capabilities <em>before</em> you&rsquo;re targeted. If it looks like you follow tight OPSEC, make it very difficult/expensive to target, or just seem like you&rsquo;re not worth the effort, you&rsquo;re less likely to be targeted. Again, it&rsquo;s a simple question of risk vs reward.</p>

<p>An unfortunate side note should be mentioned: Performing all of these tactics may make you appear to be hiding something of higher reward to them than you truly are. We know that those of us that use things like GPG are specifically targeted <a href="http://www.wired.com/2014/07/nsa-targets-users-of-privacy-services/">solely because we encrypt a message</a>. Put another way, in order to quantify the reward of targeting you, they would first need to know what you&rsquo;re doing and they likely can&rsquo;t. This will lead them to deduce whatever you&rsquo;re doing is of high value to them based on the level of OPSEC you&rsquo;ve built. Defending against being targeted makes you a target. That circle is for another day.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OPSEC of Actor vs Drug Dealer]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2016/01/23/actor-drugdealer-opsec/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2016/01/23/actor-drugdealer-opsec</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There&rsquo;s an <a href="https://theintercept.com/2016/01/12/sean-penn-el-chapo-opsec/">amazing story</a> talking about how the American actor Sean Penn accidentally gave away the location of El Chapo, the Mexican drug lord that has been on the run. The best part of the story is the OPSEC fails. I don&rsquo;t want to duplicate the article so go take a read if you want the full story. Let me summarize a few things though. From the information we&rsquo;ve gleaned, here&rsquo;s what he was doing for OPSEC:</p>

<ul>
<li>used &ldquo;mirroring&rdquo; to send messages</li>
<li>sent messages via draft folders</li>
<li>used a Blackberry Messenger, Blackphone, and burners</li>
<li>allegedly was caught because he ordered too many tacos</li>
</ul>


<h2>El Chapo</h2>

<p>The El Chapo story reminds you of the gangsters of old that were notoriously crooked, but everyone couldn&rsquo;t wait to see what they would do next. The Gangster Version of Kim Kardashian.</p>

<h2>Mirroring</h2>

<p>Enter the new OPSEC term, &ldquo;mirroring&rdquo;. At first, no one knew what this was because it&rsquo;s a made-up term for a simple OPSEC measure. It just means that communications were proxied to an intermediary party that would receive the message, and literally retype it by hand to another communication medium. The benefit here is that when El Chapo received a message, it only came from a single person which is hard to target as part of mass surveillance.</p>

<h2>Drafting</h2>

<p>If we&rsquo;re going to make up phrases, lets start calling using the Drafts folder to send messages, &ldquo;drafting&rdquo;. This is a now famous way of communicating that Al Qaeda used to do years ago and I&rsquo;m sure others used it before them. They would communicate via Yahoo mail and save messages in the drafts folder then have the recipient log in and just read the draft.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s adorably ineffective today but back then and in the 90&rsquo;s, it was actually practical. The issue was that all SMTP communications were sent in the clear and the US Government programs were literally reading every email sent because they could. By not sending an email and just saving the message into the drafts folder, there was no email to intercept and you would just have a dead drop.</p>

<p>Things have changed and we&rsquo;ve moved beyond that but the idea of the electronic dead drop is still alive.</p>

<h2>Tacoed</h2>

<p>The best story, if you want to believe it, is that the Mexican authorities ultimately caught El Chapo because the number of tacos purchased was more than it should be for a place that size. Thus, he was &ldquo;Tacoed&rdquo;.</p>

<h2>Lessons in OPSEC</h2>

<p>While some of these stories are unlikely to be true like how El Chapo was tacoed, but if you put yourself in some of their roles, I think we can learn something</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Tacoed or not, it&rsquo;s a real attack</strong>: You&rsquo;re unlikely to get tacoed anytime soon but if you believe you&rsquo;re under surveillance, what can you do to keep your purchasing patterns looking legitimate? Buying nothing is a red flag, but buying 50 pairs of pants in 50 different sizes is another red flag. Make purchases based on the type of person you&rsquo;re pretending to be. If you don&rsquo;t want anyone to know that you&rsquo;re there, maybe you shouldn&rsquo;t purchase anything at all, just go and pick it up.
<span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='You should never need to trust that the person you’re communicating with is adhering to an OPSEC plan.'></li>
<li><strong>Mirror mirror</strong>: If you have the resources to hire a crew of people to help you, sure, go ahead and mirror. It really does offer a defense from targeted mass surveillance. But just remember that whoever was transcribing the messages, was a trusted confidant of El Chapo.</li>
<li><strong>Lets stop drafting</strong>: It was a good idea back in the day but now it&rsquo;s just a tribute. I&rsquo;m all for finding interesting ways of doing a electronic dead drops like online forums, Craigslist, or blogs, but using a messaging system to save a draft is just silly. Find a medium that isn&rsquo;t specifically targeted by law enforcement and use that as a dead drop.</li>
<li><strong>Burners still good (sometimes)</strong>: We know that burners make it really hard for certain jurisdictions to track someone because it takes a few days to get a <a href="https://theintercept.com/2016/01/12/sean-penn-el-chapo-opsec/">warrant approved</a> but the NSA doesn&rsquo;t have that problem. If you can afford it, do it, but that doesn&rsquo;t mean that it&rsquo;s secure.</li>
<li><strong>Be careful talking to the OPSEC-less</strong>: I think the real story here is the difficulties that El Chapo had in talking to Sean Penn. Penn says he didn&rsquo;t know how to use computers, was given all the electronics to use, but still it required a ton of effort that he wasn&rsquo;t willing to invest. You should never need to trust that the person you&rsquo;re communicating with is adhering to an OPSEC plan. Your measures should ensure that if the other party is turned or caught, it doesn&rsquo;t point back to you. Of course this is an ideal but it&rsquo;s something you should always be thinking about when deciding if you might be burned or not.
</span></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dark Shipping: A Case Study]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2016/01/22/shipping-case-studies/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2016/01/22/shipping-case-studies</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I <a href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2016/01/02/how-to-ship-drugs/">wrote recently</a> about the risks of shipping using your country&rsquo;s shipping service and had a lot of interesting feedback. One individual which I believe has the experience raised an interesting suggestion so I thought a few case studies might be useful to discuss.</p>

<p>While not a shining example of solid OPSEC, Dread Pirate Roberts gives us a real-world perspective on what people are willing to do to ship things, illegally. Let&rsquo;s review a few of the things we know about his attempts to be dark.</p>

<h2>Case Study: DPR Is Your Roomate</h2>

<p>Ulbricht/DPR was known as <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/ryanmac/2013/10/09/living-with-ross-ulbricht-housemates-say-they-saw-no-clues-of-silk-road-or-the-dread-pirate-roberts/" title="">&ldquo;Josh&rdquo;</a> to his roomates that he met on Craigslist. He paid in cash to sublet a summer apartment in San Francisco. He arranges to pay in cash, he has no cell phone, and his current residence is a hotel near the airport. He made this seem less sketchy because he told the owners he was returning from a trip from Australia and wasn&rsquo;t on his feet yet.</p>

<p>This is a near-perfect situation. There&rsquo;s no legal record that &ldquo;Josh&rdquo; exists in this apartement but it&rsquo;s plausible that someone would want to rent it out. Josh could buy a new shirt and some jeans online to have a clean shipping record and then wait to ship his sensitive package.</p>

<ul>
<li>Good: Finding a shared location under a fake name.</li>
<li>Pretty Good: Paying in cash. This is often a red flag.</li>
<li>Bad: Not having a cell phone makes you look suspicious to normal people.</li>
<li>Bad: Craigslist is difficult to use completely anonymously. Law enforcement invest a lot of time into watching what happens on Craigslist now.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Case Study: DPR Tries To Use UPS</h2>

<p>One of the many OPSEC failures of DPR was when he went on his Google+ profile and asked if any of his contacts worked at <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2013/oct/03/five-stupid-things-dread-pirate-roberts-did-to-get-arrested">UPS, FEDEX or other private companies</a>. I believe his plan was to collect some intel on what private companies do to prevent illicit shipments or get a local hookup to pay off so that his packages weren&rsquo;t flagged.</p>

<p>The fact is there are several mandates that require private parcel companies to comply with U.S. federal laws. If for whatever reason they do not seem to adhere to these standards, the company will be fined and the business could be suspended. For publically traded companies, that&rsquo;s a very big incentive to try to catch illegal packages.</p>

<p>On the other hand, some of the very private parcel movers exist because of an expectation of privacy for their clients. Normaly this would be sending company secrets or plans for the big firm&rsquo;s merger, but the same would go for illicit deliveries. More often than not, these services are very expensive, and will not even consider taking any kind of untraceable payment.</p>

<ul>
<li>Good: Gathering intel about shipping methods.</li>
<li>Bad: Posting the request on Google+.</li>
<li>OK: Thinking about hiring a private group to ship things</li>
<li>Bad: It&rsquo;s unlikely you&rsquo;ll find a company that can ship across borders for cash or bitcoin.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Did we learn anything?</h2>

<p>Some people say they have the perfect solution and others believe it&rsquo;s not possible. I still believe that if it&rsquo;s important enough to you, you&rsquo;ll find a way to ship it. In that case, all you can do is limit your risk by not being an obvious target. You&rsquo;ll also have to decide how commited you are in terms of a time and money investment. Some of the things that DPR did require a lot of effort. He gave up his social life, his identity, and in the end, his freedom to be able to do what he wanted. Are you prepared to do theh same?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Website Fingerprinting Attacks and Defense]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2016/01/20/behavior-fingerprinting/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2016/01/20/behavior-fingerprinting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I do enjoy a deeply theoretical academic paper, but even better are those papers that take effort to determine how pragmatic an attack is. <a href="https://securewww.esat.kuleuven.be/cosic/publications/article-2456.pdf">A Critical Evaluation of Website Fingerprinting Attacks</a> takes a look at some of the theoretical attacks on Tor and see how likely they would work in the real world.</p>

<p>Better than that, it gives you a break down of the most likely attacks that users need to defend themselves against.</p>

<h2>Website Fingerprinting</h2>

<p>The attack that they&rsquo;re reviewing here shouldn&rsquo;t be confused with Browser Fingerprinting or other types of fingerprinting attacks. It refers to an adversary being able to deduce what website you&rsquo;re going to.</p>

<p>The premise in previous papers has been that on low-latency anonymity networks (like tor), attackers can analyze your connection and guess which page you&rsquo;re visiting. For example, when you go to <a href="https://www.google.com,">https://www.google.com,</a> you are visiting a page that has a predictable size, response time, and predictable number of secondary page requests being made.</p>

<h2>The Size Correlation Fingerprint</h2>

<p>One of the most rudimentary attacks is an adversary that stands between a user and Tor to see the packets being sent out and the size of the packets returned. In this simple approach, it&rsquo;s possible for an attacker that has a database of websites and their possible sizes, is able to guess which sites a user is visiting.</p>

<p><strong>Defense</strong>: &ldquo;Padding&rdquo; is considered a defense against website fingerprinting because it adds arbitrary data to your request that makes it harder for an attacker to correlate your visit to the actual website in question.</p>

<p>The Tor Project has made a decision not to implement padding. On purpose. They&rsquo;re now taking a look at research that might mean that adding small amounts of padding will have a major affect. It&rsquo;s yet to be concluded.</p>

<p>Other defenses that the paper goes into are what happens when there are multiple tabs being opened and what about the situation where something else on the network is padding things for you. The latest TBB has a nice feature that makes a separate connection in multiple tabs.</p>

<h2>The Behavioral Fingerprint</h2>

<p>One of the most discussed tactic was to take a pile of University students', watch the websites that they visit over multiple days, and then watch for similar patterns sent over Tor.</p>

<p>The basis of this attack is that you visit web pages in a linear order. You will go to your favorite news site, then Facebook, then your boyfriend&rsquo;s blog, and then your favorite shopping site. Often times, you will go in the cycle of visits multiple times over the course of a day.</p>

<p>Attackers knowing the potential sizes of pages, the loading time of a site, and other quantifiable factors, can fingerprint your browsing behavior.</p>

<p><strong>Defense</strong>: There are two options that I&rsquo;m sure you can imagine: Don&rsquo;t ever switch between dark and clear or make sure that your behavior is completely different on a dark persona.</p>

<h2>Targeted vs Untargeted</h2>

<p>There&rsquo;s a major different in the attack vectors between an adversary targeting you as an individual, versus what the paper calls a &ldquo;drag-net&rdquo; approach.</p>

<ul>
<li>Targeted attacks have less reward but are more accurate</li>
<li>Untargeted attacks have more reward but are more difficult to identify high value targets</li>
</ul>


<p>Which is most likely? While the most paranoid of us believe we are being targeted (and we should), unless you are truly a high-value target, there are not many groups trying to specifically launch a targeted attack. But a mass surveillance situation is a much more likely scenario.</p>

<p><strong>Defense</strong>: Burn, and burn often. The premise of my OPSEC model is to never give someone a chance to correlate between two different identities. If you&rsquo;re able to do that, you&rsquo;re able to defend against either of these attack scenarios.</p>

<h2>Results</h2>

<p>Long story short, some of these academic papers talking about potential attacks, take a substantial investment. That being said, we know there are organizations interested in investing those resources, but at the same time, a targeted attack on individual computers is less likely than a mass surveillance situation. Be aware that these attacks exist and never visit your favorite websites across multiple identifies.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Ship Drugs to Your House]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2016/01/02/how-to-ship-drugs/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2016/01/02/how-to-ship-drugs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You&rsquo;ve found your favorite drugs on your favorite darknets but then your OPSEC buzzer goes off and you say &ldquo;How do I actually get it shipped to me?&rdquo; Lets talk about some of the risks and likely attacks.</p>

<h2>The Fallacy Of The Drop Ship</h2>

<p>The first thing you might think is, just like your computer, find a way to be completely anonymous. That would mean sending to a &ldquo;drop ship&rdquo; location or someone else&rsquo;s house. You&rsquo;ll find documents online about how the best way to do this is:</p>

<p><img class="right" src="http://www.b3rn3d.com/images/package.png" width="400"></p>

<ul>
<li>find a house in a city that no one lives in</li>
<li>mow the lawn once week</li>
<li>let the neighbors know who you are</li>
<li>send some fake packages and receive them at the location</li>
<li>establish a pretend situation where you are there multiple times during the week.</li>
</ul>


<p>The number of people that can do this is uselessly low. If you can do this, good for you but don&rsquo;t waste your time trying to figure this situation out.</p>

<p>Lets talks talk about some pragmatic approaches.</p>

<h2>Risk Calculations</h2>

<p>To get something shipped, you must take a risk calculation. How much do you care about the package you&rsquo;re receiving, how often are you doing it, how likely are you to be caught, and what are the consequences of being caught.</p>

<pre><code>value * frequency + caught * sentence = RISK
</code></pre>

<p>This is a fabricated calculation for the sake of discussion but you can use it to come up with an arbitrary number to assign a consistent risk score and it&rsquo;s on point.</p>

<p>Lets review your situation:</p>

<ul>
<li>you plan on sending an illegal product across country, providence, or state lines</li>
<li>you plan on using a federally funded system to do so (in the case of US Mail)</li>
<li>You are plan on putting a name and address on the recipient of the illegal product</li>
</ul>


<h2>How do you do it?</h2>

<p>First: Don&rsquo;t. I know that&rsquo;s a cop out but seriously reconsider. Other options are:</p>

<ul>
<li>pick it up directly from the contact</li>
<li>agree on shipping using a private company</li>
</ul>


<p>Ok, you&rsquo;re not going to do that. If you need to, here are a few things to remember:</p>

<ul>
<li>Use your real name. I know, just do it. It is trivial for your delivery service to notice when a new name appears on an address. An out-of-country parcel to a name that doesn&rsquo;t exist is a big red flag.</li>
<li>Make yourself unlikely to be caught. Ship small packages, envelopes, low quantities. Remember that law enforcement is a career path. Johnny Law isn&rsquo;t going to make captain by nabbing a dime bag.</li>
<li>Be nice. There&rsquo;s are documents that show how delivery guys are responsible for determining if you are a sketchy person and decide that you&rsquo;re a high risk delivery.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t sign for your packages. There will always be situations where you need to but don&rsquo;t use your real signature. Have you ever noticed how your mum signs for a package?</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tor Browser vs Your Browser]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2015/12/16/tor-browser-vs-your-browser/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2015/12/16/tor-browser-vs-your-browser</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There are two main choices to use tor: Use the Tor Browser Bundle(TBB), or manually setup a computer to run tor. Maybe you&rsquo;ve spent time making a secure host and you only route traffic over tor and you&rsquo;ve employed various security protections to limit your risk, etc. So you, you say to yourself, &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t need the Tor Browser Bundle, I&rsquo;ve already installed tor.&rdquo; You would be wrong.</p>

<p>The Tor Browser (part of TBB) offers a lot of additional security protections that your &ldquo;raw&rdquo; browser doesn&rsquo;t. <a href="https://www.torproject.org/about/corepeople.html.en">Mike Perry</a> who manages the TBB portion of the Tor Project (among other things) has put in a lot of work.</p>

<p>Here are just a few reasons:</p>

<h1>Reason #1: WebRTC</h1>

<p>Here&rsquo;s a quick example: Remember the <a href="https://threatpost.com/webrtc-found-leaking-local-ip-addresses/110803/">private IP disclosure</a> vulnerability that&rsquo;s possible using WebRTC? Well the <em>only</em> browser (AFAIK) that isn&rsquo;t vulnerable to this issue is the Tor Browser. You can&rsquo;t prevent it by disabling JavaScript and you can&rsquo;t block it through an extension. And we know that Chrome, Safari, IE, and Opera aren&rsquo;t any help either.</p>

<p>This issue alone should scare you into reconsidering using a raw browser no matter how many extensions you have installed. By the way, if you&rsquo;re interested in seeing how you can disable WebRTC from firefox, it&rsquo;s a compiletime flag: <code>--disable-webrtc</code>.</p>

<h1>Unique Identifiers</h1>

<p>If I can correlate your website visit across mutiple sessions I can potentially deanonymize you in the case that you visit my site over tor and then in the clear. Even in the best case, I will still be able to watch your activities across multiple visits. What if I can correlate between when you log in as user A to those when you log in as user B.</p>

<p>There are so many situations where a malicious web page could include some kind of identifying token. The ones mitigated by TB include:</p>

<ul>
<li>HTTP auth headers (e.g. <code>http://{IDENTIFIER}username:password@website.com/</code>)</li>
<li>Cache lookup (e.g. injecting an ID into the cache and check to see if it exists on next visit)</li>
<li>Cookies (e.g. tracking cookie identified by third parties)</li>
<li>HSTS super cookies (e.g. multi-site owners can build a unique ID based on whether a user has a cached HSTS record for a particular set of domains)</li>
</ul>


<h1>Fingerprinting Defenses</h1>

<p>Fingerprinting the browser, the hardware, the user, the location, or any kind of identifying information related to a user&rsquo;s session is a very difficult attack to completely defend against. TB does what it can though to defend against this scenario. There are some crazy attacks available including:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.andlabs.org/tools/jsrecon.html">port scanning via web sockets</a></li>
<li>extracting a list of installed fonts</li>
<li><a href="https://dvcs.w3.org/hg/gamepad/raw-file/default/gamepad.html#widl-Gamepad-id">USB device enumearation via the Gamepad API</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Maybe TB hasn&rsquo;t solved this problem but the question is, what do you think your current browser is doing?</p>

<h1>Plugin Controls</h1>

<p>Your extensions/plugins/addons are terrifying. They can do whatever they want, not only to your browser, but to anything on your system. Because of this, TB has <a href="https://gitweb.torproject.org/tor-browser.git/commit/?h=tor-browser-31.6.0esr-4.5-1&amp;id=8c6604d2b776f0d8e33ed9130c5f5b8cf744bac8">patched the DNS service</a> to ensure that a browser extension doesn&rsquo;t accidentally leak your DNS requests. This is also done for OCSP so that certificate lookups must be done over the SOCKS proxy and tor.</p>

<p>Similarly, when loading the Flash or Gnash plugin, TB uses the click-to-play control so that in order to play a Flash applet, the user must explicitally click on it before it executes. The risk of Flash or any plugin for that matter goes back to whether it always adheres to proxy settings as well as what type of information is exposed to the applet. Can they obtain your local IP? Can they access a session cookie?</p>

<h1>External Event Blocking</h1>

<p>On your computer right now, you&rsquo;ve likely setup default programs associated with certain types of files. In a browser, you can also setup external programs associated to a protocol. For example <code>tel://</code>, <code>skype://</code>, or <code>ssh://</code> allows a browser to automatically send data from the browser into the associated program. There&rsquo;s a risk here that it will disclose your private info to those programs and therefore compromise your anonymity.</p>

<p>The defense in this case is present a <a href="https://gitweb.torproject.org/torbutton.git/tree/src/components/external-app-blocker.js">pop-up</a> whenever a request to leave the browser is made.</p>

<h1>History and Storage</h1>

<p>TB does everything it can to never touch your disk and never allow your browsing history to be saved to a file. There are a lot of ways <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/query?keywords=~tbb-disk-leak&amp;status=!closed">this is accomplished</a> but the risk has been that if the history or sensitive information is stored on disk, it may be accessible to other appliations or to a forensic investigator.</p>

<h1>More information</h1>

<p>There&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.torproject.org/projects/torbrowser/design/">dozens of other</a> reasons that may or may not be applicable to your plans. The point here again is, the level of effort that the Tor Browser has employed makes you question how secure your current browser configuration is.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Running Tor Browser Without the Bundle]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2015/12/15/tor-browser-bundle-without-bundle/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2015/12/15/tor-browser-bundle-without-bundle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the case that you already have Tor installed and you don&rsquo;t need the Tor Browser Bundle (TBB) to manage your tor connection, you can run it without the additinal launcher plugin.</p>

<h2>How</h2>

<ul>
<li>Download <a href="https://www.torproject.org/download/download-easy.html.en">TBB</a></li>
<li>Extract</li>
<li><p>Cd to the following directory:</p>

<pre><code>  tor-browser_en-US/Browser/TorBrowser/Data/Browser/profile.default$
</code></pre></li>
<li>Modify <code>extensions.ini</code></li>
<li><p>Comment out the following line:</p>

<pre><code>  #Extension2=/home/death/Downloads/tor-browser_en-US/Browser/TorBrowser/Data/Browser/profile.default/extensions/tor-launcher@torproject.org.xpi
</code></pre></li>
</ul>


<h2>Setup</h2>

<p>This assumes that you&rsquo;re running tor on port 9050 and ideally that you have your control port enabled with a password of &ldquo;secret&rdquo; to access it. That&rsquo;s only if you want to be able to control Tor via the browser extension. Maybe you don&rsquo;t.</p>

<p>If you want to set your password to &ldquo;sercret&rdquo; you can use tor to generate the hash for you:</p>

<pre><code>    tor --hash-password secret
</code></pre>

<p>Copy that into your /etc/torrc file under the HashedPassword section.</p>

<p>You can take a look at the other comments found in <code>start-tor-browser</code>:</p>

<pre><code>    # SETTING NAME                            VALUE
    # extensions.torbutton.banned_ports       [...],&lt;SocksPort&gt;,&lt;ControlPort&gt;
    # extensions.torbutton.block_disk         false
    # extensions.torbutton.custom.socks_host  127.0.0.1
    # extensions.torbutton.custom.socks_port  &lt;SocksPort&gt;
    # extensions.torbutton.inserted_button    true
    # extensions.torbutton.launch_warning     false
    # extensions.torbutton.loglevel           2
    # extensions.torbutton.logmethod          0
    # extensions.torbutton.settings_method    custom
    # extensions.torbutton.socks_port         &lt;SocksPort&gt;
    # extensions.torbutton.use_privoxy        false
    # extensions.torlauncher.control_port      &lt;ControlPort&gt;
    # extensions.torlauncher.loglevel          2
    # extensions.torlauncher.logmethod         0
    # extensions.torlauncher.prompt_at_startup false
    # extensions.torlauncher.start_tor         false
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arms Race to the Most Secure OS]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2015/12/04/qubes-opsec/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2015/12/04/qubes-opsec</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Snowden revelations have not only motivated people into building new security-centric tools but also to take a look at the tools we previously considered secure. This holds true for ultra-secure operating systems like <a href="https://tails.boum.org/">TAILS</a> and have created reactionary projects like <a href="https://subgraph.com/sgos/">SubgraphOS</a> and <a href="https://www.qubes-os.org/">QubesOS</a>. Let&rsquo;s take a look at the state of these projects as well as their end goals.</p>

<h1>TAILS</h1>

<p><img class="right" src="http://www.b3rn3d.com/images/tails.png" width="300">
<a href="https://tails.boum.org/">TAILS</a>, for years, has been most popular OS for the anonymous community. With official support from the Tor Project (financial and managerial), many regard this as the de facto standard.</p>

<p>The TAILS security model can be considered &ldquo;classical&rdquo; in the sense that it attempts to take an existing OS and harden to the n'th degree, add some of the privacy enhancing tools, and make sure there are no compromising flaws.</p>

<p>As stated, we are paying more attention to the secure tools that we use and this has identified some <a href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2014/07/security_vulner_4.html">fatal flaws</a> in TAILS. If you <a href="https://tails.boum.org/security/#index3h1">look back</a> at the TAILS project, the number of vulnerabilities identified and reported have are much smaller before than after Snowden disclosures.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Development</strong>: Highly active with multiple paid developers</li>
<li><strong>Maturity</strong>: First created in</li>
<li><strong>Goals</strong>: Provide an easy-to-use live environment for temporary work.</li>
<li><strong>Roadmap</strong>: Continue same model and further harden the OS.</li>
<li><strong>Challenges</strong>:

<ul>
<li>Minimal support for persistence (besides files). Not designed to be installed but just run once.</li>
<li>No mitigations for GCHQ/NSA type low level hardware attacks</li>
<li>The focus on supporting all forms of users may affect security</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2>Qubes OS</h2>

<p><img class="right" src="http://www.b3rn3d.com/images/qubes.png" width="300">
I&rsquo;ll start by saying this is the project I&rsquo;m rooting for. <a href="https://www.qubes-os.org/">QubesOS</a> starts with the premise that your OS <em>will</em> be exploited. Your browser will exploit you, your storage device will attack your computer, you mail client will try and attack your web browser. To mitigate these risks, they were the first project to successfully implement a compartmentalization model using a hypervisor (as opposed to Linux kernel controls) using XEN.</p>

<p>If that seems too abstract, here&rsquo;s an example: You want to sell illicit things on the darknet. In Qubes, you build a new WHONIX instance running TBB and all your activities are done in that context.</p>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='it works similar to how I write about OSPEC: Everything is a separate identity, one identity does not touch the other, when you are done with an identity, burn it. Replace the word “identity” with “virtual object” and you have their security model'>
Technical details aside for a moment, it works similar to how I write about OSPEC: Everything is a separate identity, one identity does not touch the other, when you are done with an identity, burn it. Replace the word &ldquo;identity&rdquo; with &ldquo;virtual object&rdquo; and you have their security model.</p>

<p>This is accomplished by making several virtual objects. You virtualize your firewall, you virtualize your USB controller, you virtualize the browser you&rsquo;re using for Project A, and separately, you virtualize the browser you&rsquo;re using for Project B. From here, QubesOS helps facilitate communications between those objects if necessary.
</span></p>

<p>QubesOS offers some features that no other system currently offers. The big one for me is virtualization for USB controller. So no only are you creating virtual machines, you&rsquo;re creating virtual controllers. If someone malicious is plugged into your system, even in the case of an [0-day exploiting the firmware of your USB controller], the rest of your system is not compromised.</p>

<p>The other major feature that we know is in the GCHQ playbook is protection from WiFi driver exploits. We&rsquo;ve heard of this exploit being used in the while but have yet to have a real mitigation from it. With QubesOS, your wireless card is its own virtual object that contains the exploit into its own virtual machine.</p>

<p>There is a lot more to talk about with QubesOS but it does seem the one to watch going forward.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Development</strong>: Active but a small group.</li>
<li><strong>Maturity</strong>: v3.1 released is functional but not perfect.</li>
<li><strong>Roadmap</strong>: Investing time in rebuilding the UI is a priority.</li>
<li><strong>Challenges</strong>:

<ul>
<li>Hardware support is difficult to predict. They have an approved list but you can&rsquo;t assume it will work on all systems.</li>
<li>Performance is relatively poor to the other systems and Qubes consumes a lot of memory for each of the virtual machines.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2>SubgraphOS</h2>

<p><img class="right" src="http://www.b3rn3d.com/images/subgraph.png" width="300">
<a href="https://subgraph.com/sgos/">SubgraphOS</a> is in the same category as Qubes where it is focusing its efforts to leverage containerization into the system to compartmentalize application. Then an abstraction layer is placed on top to provide communication between said objects.</p>

<p>The main difference between QubesOS and SubgraphOS is that it uses Linux containers as opposed to XEN objects.</p>

<p>The problem thus far is that only a small group of people have seen SubgraphOS working. I&rsquo;m also concerned about the development of SubgraphOS by the company, Subgraph. We know that Subgraph is a <a href="https://subgraph.com/about-us/index.en.html">&ldquo;security&rdquo; company</a> that aims to provide services and products to its clients. The other two projects discussed here have been community projects and money is not the primary goal. The owner of the company comes from the secure kernel world where he was a mod of one of the most popular and dramatic bug hunting mailing lists.</p>

<p>SubgraphOS had the problem of being announced way too soon. They showed off the now famous <a href="https://subgraph.com/img/sgos.png">SubgraphOS images</a> that caught everyone&rsquo;s eye before there was anything to actually look at.</p>

<p>I come from the perspective of seeing tons of projects die in the past. The ones that I&rsquo;ve seen stick through are not usually (ever?) the ones released for free by a money making company.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Development</strong>: Probably active? Not open to the public.</li>
<li><strong>Maturity</strong>: Immature, pre-alpha releases</li>
<li><strong>Roadmap</strong>: Hopefully release a beta to the public soon.</li>
<li><strong>Challenges</strong>:

<ul>
<li>Money may affect the development of the product.</li>
<li>Closed development may deter acceptance of even a finished product.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Camgirl OPSEC]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2015/10/22/bad-camgirl-opsec/"/>
    <updated>2015-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2015/10/22/bad-camgirl-opsec</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you read this <a href="http://motherboard.vice.com/read/camgirl-opsec-how-the-worlds-newest-porn-stars-protect-their-privacy-online">interesting post</a> from the nice people over at Vice, it covers a few items about good OPSEC when you have the threat of stalkers as part of your threat model.</p>

<h2>Low Tech But High Investment</h2>

<p><img class="right" src="http://www.b3rn3d.com/images/badgirl.jpg" width="300"></p>

<p>You don&rsquo;t expect that an overzealous camgirl fan to be able to do facial recognition, but we know that services like Google and Facebook can offer <a href="http://www.facesearch.com/">this service</a> for free! Doing a reverse image lookup or trying to look at a photo&rsquo;s metadata are really simple things that just about any low life can figure out.</p>

<p>The more serious weapon that they have is not technology, but commitment and drive. They will do anything in their power to try and find out information about you.</p>

<h2>Recommendations</h2>

<p><strong>Buy Burner Everything</strong>: We&rsquo;ve heard about burner phones but don&rsquo;t forget about a dedicated cam girl laptop, and more importantly camgirl camera used only for your online business.</p>

<p>Your camera can tell a lot about you. The optics, resolution, capabilities are all fingerprintable metrics. If a perv is able to find another photo series using the same expensive equipment, it may be be possible for them to find that you&rsquo;re cross-posting dirty pictures on other sites like Facebook.</p>

<p><strong>Do Your Homework On The Service:</strong> The article mentions using a VPN of course. This is important as a fall back but it&rsquo;s important that the camgirl service being used does everything it can to protect your IP from being leaked. Ask questions to the service about whether IPs are logged and who has access to that information. How do you create accounts and how do you recover your password if it&rsquo;s lost? Which brings us to a reminder about account security.</p>

<p><strong>Secure Your Accounts:</strong> Does the cam service let you reset your password by answering a few personal questions? Are these questions that someone that is a super-fan would know by chatting with you? Find a cam service that provides two-factor security so that you enter in a user name, a password, and then you have to enter in a One-Time-Password. This will help ensure that no one is able to get in even if they guess what your password is. In my &ldquo;research&rdquo; I have found only once service that provides this type of security. And of course, choose a strong password.</p>

<p><strong>Build a List Of Lies:</strong> There is no good defense against someone that is going to do everything they can to try and get you to leak information about yourself. As I&rsquo;ve discussed before, don&rsquo;t tell them what you don&rsquo;t want them to know. Lie to them.</p>

<p>If someone asks you about your coffee table and you realize it was made two streets down from your current location, don&rsquo;t say &ldquo;Sorry I can&rsquo;t tell you.&rdquo; You&rsquo;ve confirmed to the adversary a piece of sensitive information that they will likely target at another time. Lie to them. Tell them it&rsquo;s a popular brand purchased from a popular store that is popular in your entire country.</p>

<p>Come up with a list of lies so that you can remember to maintain them. This could include:</p>

<ul>
<li>Name</li>
<li>Country of origin</li>
<li>Age of your house</li>
<li>Brothers, sisters, family members and their names</li>
<li>Previous relationships</li>
<li>Favorite band, music, politician, TV show, movie, book, etc.</li>
<li>University and expertise</li>
<li>Professional employment</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Hide In The Darkness:</strong> If you live cam at 17:00 every day, and you do it by a window, they not only will be able to deduce what timezone you&rsquo;re in, but also how far North you live. Those camgirls that live in the Scottish Highlands will have a lot less daylight towards Winter, something that an attacker would notice.</p>

<p><strong>Tell Your Friends About Your Policy:</strong> You might be embarrassed about being a cam'er and telling your friends about it is the worst idea. But consider this, if someone finds out that you are a cam girl, are you sure that friend won&rsquo;t leak your information.</p>

<p>When someone finds out that you are friends with someone else, their gears will automatically shift to finding out about them. Do they have the same OPSEC policy as you? Do they have an open Facebook account? Do they have any other pictures of you that they&rsquo;re willing to sell?</p>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='It’s always better to confide in someone a secret, than risk they find out on their own.'>
It seems bad opsec to disclose a secret but it is counterintuitive. It&rsquo;s always better to confide in someone a secret, than risk they find out on their own. By letting them in on the secret, and showing them how serious the secret is to you, you are asking them to join in to protect that secret. Without doing so ahead of time, there is no social contract that would imply this.
</span></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Evading Stylometry Attacks Using VIM Spellcheck]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2015/09/22/stylometric-evasions-with-spellcheck/"/>
    <updated>2015-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2015/09/22/stylometric-evasions-with-spellcheck</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We&rsquo;ve discussed the concerns of <a href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/01/31/tools-styometrics/">stylometric attacks</a> and how good adversaries are at it today. There are only a few tools that attempt to anonymize your writing style and none so far can do it inline. But there&rsquo;s help.</p>

<p>If you are concerned about these types of attacks you can start customizing your favorite writing application (VIM, Kate, etc) to leverage syntax highlighting as a way of pointing out when you&rsquo;re stylometrically leaking information.</p>

<p>For example, when I write, I often say &ldquo;for example&rdquo; and while this is a common phrase, it can be used to begin to help fingerprinting your writing style across multiple sources of text. In VIM, you can use custom spell check to highlight certain syntax or just use the spell checker to highlight the fact that you&rsquo;re using buzz phrases like &ldquo;the fact that&rdquo;.</p>

<h2>VIM</h2>

<p>Here&rsquo;s a way to add your favorite words to the VIM spell check list as a bad word. Whenever you use that word, VIM will prompt you in red that it&rsquo;s been misspelled. By definition, everyone&rsquo;s common words are different so you&rsquo;ll need to review some of your recent writings' grammar, as well as help you find which words to add.</p>

<ul>
<li>Enable spell check in your .vimrc file by adding the following line:</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>set spell spelllang=en_gb</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<ul>
<li>Add &ldquo;bad words&rdquo; in VIM by putting the cursor over a word and sending &ldquo;zW&rdquo;. This will add it to VIM&rsquo;s internal bad word list.</li>
</ul>


<p>Now whenever you type that word, VIM will automatically red-flag it to remind you that you may not want to use it.</p>

<h2>Grammar</h2>

<p>This is a poor mans way of defending against stylometric attacks and I would recommend attempting to use tools like <a href="https://github.com/psal/anonymouth">Anonymouth</a> to help you anonymize your writings, but sometimes you just need a reminder that you use a phrase too often.</p>

<h2>UPDATE</h2>

<p>If you want to at least do a frequency analysis of the words in your text, it&rsquo;s pretty easy to do. The following is an example in python. If you run this and provide an argument of your text file, it will give you a break down of your most common words, hopefully to help you determine what words you could be attributed to using most often.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span>stemmer.py </span></figcaption>
<div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
<span class='line-number'>20</span>
<span class='line-number'>21</span>
<span class='line-number'>22</span>
<span class='line-number'>23</span>
<span class='line-number'>24</span>
<span class='line-number'>25</span>
<span class='line-number'>26</span>
<span class='line-number'>27</span>
<span class='line-number'>28</span>
<span class='line-number'>29</span>
<span class='line-number'>30</span>
<span class='line-number'>31</span>
<span class='line-number'>32</span>
<span class='line-number'>33</span>
<span class='line-number'>34</span>
<span class='line-number'>35</span>
<span class='line-number'>36</span>
<span class='line-number'>37</span>
<span class='line-number'>38</span>
<span class='line-number'>39</span>
<span class='line-number'>40</span>
<span class='line-number'>41</span>
<span class='line-number'>42</span>
<span class='line-number'>43</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='python'><span class='line'><span class="c">#!/usr/bin/python</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c"># Author: b3rn3d</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c"># Based on: http://www.nltk.org/api/nltk.stem.html</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c"># Usage: ./stemmer.py filename.txt</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="kn">import</span> <span class="nn">re</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="kn">import</span> <span class="nn">sys</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">try</span><span class="p">:</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kn">from</span> <span class="nn">Stemmer</span> <span class="kn">import</span> <span class="n">Stemmer</span> <span class="k">as</span> <span class="n">SS</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">except</span><span class="p">:</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">print</span> <span class="s">&quot;Stemmer/Snowball not installed. Please install it via apt-get install python-stemmer&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">sys</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">exit</span><span class="p">()</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">if</span> <span class="ow">not</span> <span class="nb">len</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">sys</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">argv</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="mi">2</span><span class="p">:</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">print</span> <span class="s">&quot;FAIL: Supply test file to analyze.&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">sys</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">exit</span><span class="p">()</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="n">f</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nb">open</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">sys</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">argv</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">])</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="n">text</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s">&quot;&quot;</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">join</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">f</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">readlines</span><span class="p">())</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c">#extract words</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="n">words</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="p">[</span><span class="n">word</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">lower</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="k">for</span> <span class="n">word</span> <span class="ow">in</span> <span class="n">re</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">findall</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s">r&#39;\w+&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">text</span><span class="p">)]</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="n">stemmer</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">SS</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s">&#39;english&#39;</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="n">counts</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nb">dict</span><span class="p">()</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c">#count stems and extract shortest words possible</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">for</span> <span class="n">word</span> <span class="ow">in</span> <span class="n">words</span><span class="p">:</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="n">stem</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">stemmer</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">stemWord</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">word</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">if</span> <span class="n">stem</span> <span class="ow">in</span> <span class="n">counts</span><span class="p">:</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="n">shortest</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">count</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">counts</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="n">stem</span><span class="p">]</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="k">if</span> <span class="nb">len</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">word</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="o">&lt;</span> <span class="nb">len</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">shortest</span><span class="p">):</span>
</span><span class='line'>            <span class="n">shortest</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">word</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="n">counts</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="n">stem</span><span class="p">]</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="n">shortest</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">count</span><span class="o">+</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">else</span><span class="p">:</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="n">counts</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="n">stem</span><span class="p">]</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">word</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c">#convert {key: (word, count)} to [(word, count, key)] for convenient sort and print</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="n">output</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="p">[</span><span class="n">wordcount</span> <span class="o">+</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="n">root</span><span class="p">,)</span> <span class="k">for</span> <span class="n">root</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">wordcount</span> <span class="ow">in</span> <span class="n">counts</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">items</span><span class="p">()]</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c">#trick to sort output by count (descending) &amp; word (alphabetically)</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="n">output</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">sort</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">key</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="k">lambda</span> <span class="n">x</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="o">-</span><span class="n">x</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">],</span><span class="n">x</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">]))</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">for</span> <span class="n">item</span> <span class="ow">in</span> <span class="n">output</span><span class="p">:</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">print</span> <span class="s">&#39;</span><span class="si">%s</span><span class="s">:</span><span class="si">%d</span><span class="s"> (Root: </span><span class="si">%s</span><span class="s">)&#39;</span> <span class="o">%</span> <span class="n">item</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lie to Me, Please]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2015/09/22/lie-to-me/"/>
    <updated>2015-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2015/09/22/lie-to-me</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can always tell how important a secret is to you by how many people you tell and the way you keep the secret. That is to say, when hiding whether or not you were dating So-and-So, you might coyly smirk &ndash; a simple tell for anyone to determine you&rsquo;re lying and that&rsquo;s exactly your intention: to gain more attention. But when you killed someone in a hit-and-run for example, there&rsquo;s no coy smirk on your face when you adamantly deny it. These two types of lies are an important differentiation to realize when protecting yourself.</p>

<p>If you have an interesting project that needs to be kept secret, it may be hard to maintain the discipline of keeping it a secret. Often, the vanity of your project will tempt you to share the details with someone else even though you know it is safer to keep them a secret. In hindsight, you&rsquo;ll come to realize that you&rsquo;ve created a liability but for those few moments of discussion, you will irrationally determine it was worth it.</p>

<p><img class="right" src="http://www.b3rn3d.com/images/conversation.png" width="400"></p>

<p>In hacker OPSEC the first rule is of course we don&rsquo;t talk about OPSEC. And that, just like in Fight Club, is the first rule that is broken. We have friends that we&rsquo;d like to share information with, or we disclose a small portion of a secret that leads to questions about that secret. If this doesn&rsquo;t make sense, let me present you a conversation:</p>

<p>A: I wonder what $Company does for their physical security system.
B: Well&hellip; they actually do X, Y, and Z.
A: How do you know that?</p>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='People feel more comfortable being blatantly lied to as opposed to telling them that they can’t find out the truth.'>
Now you may coyly reply with &ldquo;I&rsquo;m sorry I can&rsquo;t tell you&rdquo; with an all-knowing smirk, or if that truly was information you&rsquo;re protecting, you lie. And this is my point: People feel more comfortable being blatantly lied to as opposed to telling them that they can&rsquo;t find out the truth.
</span></p>

<p>I bring this up because this should be remembered from two points of view. The first from your own perspective: you should never break the first rule of opsec and hopefully never lead someone into asking you these types of questions. The second reason is to bring attention to those that talk this way and how they are leaking intel.</p>

<p>In most cases, those people that say they are hiding something, are usually not. The coy smiles are a way of appearing interesting without the threat of actually requiring to be interesting. In these cases, you can easily define whether the person could become a resource or should discarded.</p>

<p>In summary, make sure you lie to people. Ideally it should be a well thought through lie but if you don&rsquo;t have that, say something&hellip; anything. A stupid lie is much better than saying nothing or that you can&rsquo;t tell them because it makes the other party more interested. This type of attention is not something you usually want.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Analyzing Trust and Secret Disclosure]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2015/08/22/secret-disclosures/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2015/08/22/secret-disclosures</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>OPSEC and relationships are often opposing forces. You’ve spent months perfecting your OPSEC for a campaign when your friend walks in and says “Ooh what’s that.” Or you signifigant other finds a file marked “Super juicy secret.” I do believe that humans are social beings no matter how hard we try. Even nerds that stay home will end up yearning for personal  contact in some way. How do you determine if you should share a secret with another person and build a relationship with that person at the risk of compromising your campaign?</p>

<p><img class="right" src="http://www.b3rn3d.com/images/relationships.jpg" width="400"></p>

<p>Look at the OPSEC measures that the members of lulzsec used. They all trusted eachother and everyone knew other peoples names, and in some cases addresses. This relationship of trust ended up being their downfall.</p>

<h2>Example</h2>

<p>Let us start with a secret for sake of discussion: I have a laptop riddled with Taylor Swift songs.</p>

<p>My OPSEC campaign includes that I’ve encrypted my laptop so that even with access, the songs would be difficult to find. I hide my laptop in a broom closet. The broom closet for some reason has a lock on it. But still there are days when I really want to listen to my favorite Swift jam and because I live with my mother, she catches me rocking out.</p>

<p>In this case, its straight forward. Your mother is the adversary, she can never know about Taylor Swift songs and you’ve likely done a better job at hiding.</p>

<p>But what about the situation where you are hanging out with a friend and notice that she is an avid Taylor Swift fan and if you share this commonality with her, you might establish a deeper relationship.</p>

<h2>The Three Disclosure Tactics</h2>

<p>I’ve found that people handle this in three potential tactics when disclosing a secret:</p>

<ol>
<li>You decide that you can trust this person and privately disclose that you are a Taylor Swift fan.</li>
<li>You drop hints that you may or may know something about Taylor but you’re unwilling to disclose it out-right to just anyone but secretly hope that the other person will ask you about it.</li>
<li>You don’t let on that you’re into TS at all.</li>
</ol>


<p>These are stupid situations but these are how most people handle secrets.</p>

<h2>Trusted Disclosure</h2>

<p>Option 1, trusted disclosure is where you analyze the relationship with the other person, look at the risk involved in disclosing, and the potential reward that exists if you do share. This is what some may call “normal” in terms of relationships. You decide that you will disclose a secret to a trusted person and expect that the trusted person does not use this information against you. If for example, you know that the other party has worthwhile knowledge related to your secret, the reward may outweigh the risk that the disclosure is used to exploit you.</p>

<h2>Plausibly Deniable Disclosure</h2>

<p>In option 2, plausibly deniable disclosure, you hint that you might have a secret but you can still plausibly deny that the secret exists. There is less analysis of risk vs reward or analysis of the trust of the person so you’ll often hear people leak this in public. “I might know something about X but I can’t tell you”. If you go to DEFCON, you will hear this just about every day.</p>

<p>This is the most common tactic with people missing social contact/relationships and let their ego get in the way. This either means that the secret being kept is not that risky of a secret, or the person is not disciplined enough to follow opsec. In either case, frowned upon in terms of OPSEC.</p>

<h2>Zero Knowledge</h2>

<p>The last option is not a disclosure at all but maintains a zero knowledge relationship going forward. In terms of OPSEC, you can consider this a firewall rule that blocks all by default. In this scenario you get no reward, no commonality in the relationship, and no benefit besides the fact that you can keep in your pocket that you have a secret in-depth knowledge of a subject that may be of interest to the subject. Because remember, knowledge is power and knowledge of someone’s knowledge is a power you may not want to concede.</p>

<p>Be disciplined. Be in control. Make active decisions about your disclosures and your relationships.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Risks of Relationships]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2015/07/04/opsec-relationships/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2015/07/04/opsec-relationships</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I don&rsquo;t often write about myself but for examples purposes, I will disclose that I&rsquo;ve recently entered into a relationship with a person for the first time in a long time. While this is exciting for me and also sad, the idea of how to handle relationships while maintaining OPSEC is a minefield.</p>

<h2>Trust</h2>

<p>The first thing you&rsquo;re told in any relationship be it with a signifigant other, a family member, or a friend, is that trust is key. You should be able to confid in the other person about your darkest secrets.</p>

<p>For some of us, our darkest secrets are not things to disclose to the SO. Not because you&rsquo;re selfish or don&rsquo;t trust the other, but because some disclosures make the other liable (a legal term).</p>

<h2>Identity Division</h2>

<p>In other cases, you&rsquo;ve created a new identity that has nothing to do with your IRL identity in which case, these secrets have nothing to do with the other person. If you&rsquo;ve created an OPSEC campaign where you&rsquo;ve properly divided all of your personal relationships from your online identity, you are no longer that person.</p>

<p>This, admittedly, is a rationalization of a complicated issue that I have not, nor plan to in the near future, discuss with my SO. I suggest that you do the same.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ego and OPSEC]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2015/02/04/ego-and-opsec/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2015/02/04/ego-and-opsec</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you&rsquo;ve been <a href="http://www.htxt.co.za/2015/02/04/silk-road-trial-closes-would-dread-pirate-roberts-do-that/">following the DPR story</a> you&rsquo;ll notice that the prosecution paints DPR as an ego-maniac willing to do anything to gain more and more power and money. It doesn&rsquo;t matter if a lawyer is right, but the picture that it paints highlights a challenge that humans have with OPSEC, their ego.</p>

<p><img class="right" src="http://www.b3rn3d.com/images/ego.jpg" width="400"></p>

<p>As you go dark, moving away from what would be your normal life (or fractioning off from it) has a novelty to it. It feels fun, and exciting, and you feel like you&rsquo;re doing something interesting. This is your ego kicking you in the back of the head and if you feel it at first, you&rsquo;ll know it&rsquo;s going to be a problem going forward. As the novelty wears off, your OPSEC becomes more of a discipline than a game. You follow your procedures and lock yourself down, but you sigh at how it&rsquo;s arduous compared to the everyday consumer.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;ve continued this far, and you haven&rsquo;t broken protocol, the feeling of isolation and loneliness creeps in. Similar to what U.S. and U.K soldiers deal with when given high clearances. You can&rsquo;t talk about what you did, are doing, or will be doing otherwise the results will be devastating.</p>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='Without this feeling of success fueling your ego, your self-esteem begins to deteriorate, and your motivation turns into self-discipline.'>
Even if your natural tendency is not to be an outwardly confident person, your mind automatically has a need to feel pride for the work that it&rsquo;s doing. Similar to how a school janitor is proud of her job, and takes it as serious as the medical doctor, your brain will automatically rationalize your success relative to your surroundings. Without this feeling of success fueling your ego, your self-esteem begins to deteriorate, and your motivation turns into self-discipline.
</span></p>

<h2>DPR Ego Mistakes</h2>

<p>The DPR case is a perfect reminder. Thus far, the story goes that DPR was caught at a library because he walked away from his computer while it was still running. He kept a backup copy of the Silk Road software on his nightstand. He originally created Silk Road as a clearnet domain, silkroad.org and then took that down. He kept a journal of all of his activities while he was dark and even referenced personal details like travel plans and medical issues.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s easy to conclude that DPR is a young, naive kid without any plans to truly defend against the type of surveillance that he was put under. That may be true but I would like to suggest that he succumb to the natural human tendency to share with someone the fame and power that he had created. To let people in on how accomplished (in his own mind) he had become. As the fame of Silk Road increased, so did his need to take a little credit.</p>

<h2>Alter ego</h2>

<p>The alter ego is supposed to be a split off of your personality, have different motivators, different skills, different temperament. In many ways this is a powerful asset as an OPSEC expert, yet difficult to achieve. Even up achieving, you will continue to be a slave to feeding that alter ego&rsquo;s, ego, so don&rsquo;t ignore it.</p>

<h2>Lessons Learned</h2>

<p>It might be easy to say &ldquo;I&rsquo;ll just not pay attention to my ego&rdquo; but this would be a challenge that Eastern Religions have tried teach individuals for years and years. Your ego plays an important part of your psyche and there may be tricks to ignore it, but it&rsquo;s easier to accept it and learn how to feed it. If your operations have an outcome, ensure that you take the time to appreciate that you have achieved your goals. You can even take some of the motivators out of a weight-loss book and set a celebratory event based on the success of your operation.</p>

<p>Buy yourself that cake. You deserve it. Just remember to eat it in the darkness. :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[XKeyScore Source Code Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/07/04/xkeyscore-source-code-review/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/07/04/xkeyscore-source-code-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://boingboing.net/2014/07/03/if-you-read-boing-boing-the-n.html">recent revelations from Jake Applebaum, et all today</a>, highlight some not-to-be-understated revelations.</p>

<ul>
<li>Tor users are directly targeted</li>
<li>TAILS users are directly targeted</li>
<li>People searching for privacy tools are targeted</li>
</ul>


<p>While the conclusion by some may have been &ldquo;well of course the NSA is doing that&rdquo; the revelation and the insight it provides is direct, specific evidence that people worried about their privacy are being attacked. More-over, this provides further evidence that the NSA&rsquo;s goal is to <a href="http://www.democracynow.org/2014/5/13/collect_it_all_glenn_greenwald_on">collect it all</a>.</p>

<h2>The Revelations</h2>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='privacy-conscious bystanders are targeted: Tor users, people that visit the Tor website, people that use TAILS, or try to view hidden services'>
To summarize, the source code to the NSA program, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/XKeyscore">XKeyscore</a> (known since the early days of the Snowden disclosures) has been leaked. It sounds like the program&rsquo;s entire source code is in the hands of another party and it shows what the code does, how it works and who it&rsquo;s targeting. We now know that privacy-conscious bystanders are targeted: Tor users, people that visit the Tor website, people that use TAILS, or try to view hidden services. Each of these are considered suspicious activities and flagged as the IP&rsquo;s of suspects by NSA&rsquo;s network monitoring machine.  This is further a reminder that if you look like you are privacy conscious, you are going to be a targeted as an &ldquo;extremist&rdquo; in the eyes of the United States and it&rsquo;s allies.
</span></p>

<h2>Tracking Bridge Users</h2>

<p>XKeyscore is tracking the IP addresses that are sending emails to the Tor bridge automated account. When a user is in a country that blocks Tor, they have an option to use an unlisted Tor entry node called bridges. To get an unlisted bridge IP, one of the options is to email a Tor Project email address which auto-replies with an address of a bridge. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Five_Eyes">Five Eyes</a> have been documenting each IP that makes a request to that email address.</p>

<h2>Tracking Tor Directory Authorities</h2>

<p>Another facet disclosed was that the NSA are targeting a specific Tor directory server run by Sebastian Hahn. I believe that this is the case only because the source of the XKeycode leak was by a node in Germany. Looking at nodes in other countries, would point to a corresponding directory authority in that region.</p>

<p>Until relatively recently, the Tor Network consisted of only 9 directory servers of which all clients would first make a connection to prior to joining the Tor network. These 9 directory servers are still in place, but an additional feature lets Tor nodes act as a directory server cache. With this feature, you weren&rsquo;t automatically required to connect to one of the directory authorities during each bootup. This helps mitigate this risk.</p>

<h2>Tracking Tor Entry Nodes</h2>

<p>Even if your connection to the directory authorities were not caught by the program, your connections to the Tor entry nodes were. So while directory authorities were only used during boot, the connections to Tor entry nodes were used repeatedly as your client will build a circuit.</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s not much you can do to defend against this one. Using a bridge would ensure that XKeyScore won&rsquo;t know which IP&rsquo;s to track, but the requests for bridges are caught as well. One may consider running their own unlisted Tor entry node, which is possible, but it severely degrades your anonymity. Users concerned with this may consider using a VPN service and then connecting over Tor. This would not fix it, but it would make it more difficult to identify the originating request to connect to Tor.</p>

<h2>Tracking Torproject.org Visits</h2>

<p>One of the more useless network iterations that are logged is that of users visiting www.torproject.org. The document shows what they are calling &ldquo;microplugins&rdquo; that highlight specific pieces of information that are caught in transit. Your visit to the Tor Project&rsquo;s website logged and you are now flagged as suspicious.</p>

<h2>XKeyScore Code</h2>

<p>The most interesting part is the code released showing how XKeyScore works. Many have already highlighted that the NSA programs are merely malicious implementations of existing technology (as opposed to custom software built from the ground up). We can see that XKeyScore&rsquo;s database uses a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mapreduce">MapReduce</a> model. One very common with NoSQL databases like Hadoop. This is hinted in the &ldquo;mapper&rdquo; and &ldquo;reducer&rdquo; functions that searches for onion addresses:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
<span class='line-number'>20</span>
<span class='line-number'>21</span>
<span class='line-number'>22</span>
<span class='line-number'>23</span>
<span class='line-number'>24</span>
<span class='line-number'>25</span>
<span class='line-number'>26</span>
<span class='line-number'>27</span>
<span class='line-number'>28</span>
<span class='line-number'>29</span>
<span class='line-number'>30</span>
<span class='line-number'>31</span>
<span class='line-number'>32</span>
<span class='line-number'>33</span>
<span class='line-number'>34</span>
<span class='line-number'>35</span>
<span class='line-number'>36</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>mapper&lt;onion_t>: 
</span><span class='line'>      static const std::string prefix = "anonymizer/tor/hiddenservice/address/";
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>      onion_t onion;
</span><span class='line'>      size_t matches = cur_args()->matches.size();
</span><span class='line'>      for (size_t pos=0; pos &lt; matches; ++pos) \{
</span><span class='line'>        const std::string &value = match(pos);
</span><span class='line'>        if (value.size() == 16)
</span><span class='line'>          onion.set_address(value);
</span><span class='line'>        else if(!onion.has_scheme())
</span><span class='line'>          onion.set_scheme(value);
</span><span class='line'>        else
</span><span class='line'>          onion.set_port(value);
</span><span class='line'>      \}
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>      if (!onion.has_address())
</span><span class='line'>        return false;
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>      MAPPER.map(onion.address(), onion);
</span><span class='line'>      xks::fire_fingerprint(prefix + onion.address());
</span><span class='line'>      return true;
</span><span class='line'>  
</span><span class='line'>    reducer&lt;onion_t>:
</span><span class='line'>      for (values_t::const_iterator iter = VALUES.begin();
</span><span class='line'>          iter != VALUES.end();
</span><span class='line'>          ++iter) {
</span><span class='line'>        DB["tor_onion_survey"]["onion_address"] = iter->address() + ".onion";
</span><span class='line'>        if (iter->has_scheme())
</span><span class='line'>          DB["tor_onion_survey"]["onion_scheme"] = iter->scheme();
</span><span class='line'>        if (iter->has_port())
</span><span class='line'>          DB["tor_onion_survey"]["onion_port"] = iter->port();
</span><span class='line'>        DB["tor_onion_survey"]["onion_count"] = boost::lexical_cast&lt;std::string>(TOTAL_VALUE_COUNT);
</span><span class='line'>        DB.apply();
</span><span class='line'>        DB.clear();
</span><span class='line'>      }
</span><span class='line'>      return true;</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<h2>Full Code</h2>

<p>Below is the full code released:
<a href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/assets/xkeyscorerules100.txt">xkeyscorerules100.txt</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Privacy Controls as a Fingerprinting Attack]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/06/22/privacy-controls-for-fingerprinting/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/06/22/privacy-controls-for-fingerprinting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Privacy conscious websites and applications often give you privacy controls like &ldquo;opt'ing-out&rdquo; of using your browsing habits for statistics, or setting whether or not to share your profile information. If you&rsquo;ve already done your job to ensure that you are not sharing any sensitive information, these pseudo-privacy controls may put you at a high risk of being labeled a suspicious account.</p>

<h2>How Privacy Controls Actually Work</h2>

<p>Lets take, for example, a forum where you can make changes to your settings to not include your information in the anonymized statistics gathering. Does that mean that your activities will not be tracked now that you have clicked the opt-out check box? In most cases, all this means is that your activities will not be used for statistics and reporting, but your activities will continue be logged.</p>

<p>In many cases, what happens in the backend is there will be an &ldquo;opt-out&rdquo; value assigned to your user account. A database contains your account information, your settings, and then a single True or False value dictating whether you&rsquo;ve opt-out. A simple query of this database will return all users in the system that have decided to opt-out.</p>

<p>One specific example is the popular <a href="http://www.simplemachines.org/">Simple Machines Forum</a> which retains a value in the database named &ldquo;private.&rdquo; This is just an integer that controls the various levels of privacy control on your forum profile.</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>if (isset($modSettings['smfVersion']) && $modSettings['smfVersion'] &lt;= '2.0 Beta 1')
</span><span class='line'>{
</span><span class='line'>  upgrade_query("
</span><span class='line'>  UPDATE {$db_prefix}custom_fields
</span><span class='line'>  SET private = 2
</span><span class='line'>  WHERE private = 1");
</span><span class='line'>}</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<h2>Enabling the Privacy Zealot Flag</h2>

<p>The problem, as you can see, is that you are vulnerable to a type of fingerprinting attack. If law enforcement wanted find the highest risk accounts on a system, they would not want to weed through thousands of accounts or use expensive <a href="http://www.palantir.com">analytical software</a>. They they will partition the accounts in the simplest means necessary, one of which being users who have decided to opt-out or have enabled the various privacy features.</p>

<h2>Target Selection</h2>

<p>The concept of specifically targeting users concerned about privacy, and labeling them potential subjects, is nothing new. We&rsquo;ve heard it happen with journalists, activists, and especially pregnant women. If you haven&rsquo;t read it yet, check out the article, <a href="http://time.com/83200/privacy-internet-big-data-opt-out/">Here&rsquo;s what happened when I tried to hide my pregnancy from the Internet and marketing companies</a> about what happens when you actually go through all the steps to protect your privacy.</p>

<h2>Defense</h2>

<p>Why opt-out? Ask yourself &ldquo;what does this privacy feature actually do?&rdquo; In most cases, the anonymous statistics that a web application collects, are less of a risk to your privacy than the possibility that an account be given the &ldquo;privacy zealot&rdquo; flag. Your first goal when trying to maintain your anonymity and defend against similar attacks, is to do everything you can to not become a target of interest. This includes:</p>

<ul>
<li>Not enabling any settings on your account that may make you look concerned about your privacy</li>
<li>Keeping your browser configuration similar to other users of that system (e.g. JavaScript enabled, commong UserAgent)</li>
<li>Being aware of phrases that could make you a target. Check out <a href="http://pastebin.com/yDicWqb2">the list of NSA keywords</a> to see the types of words they key in on.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fingerprinting Attacks on Screen Resolution]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/05/29/fingerprinting-resolution/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.b3rn3d.com/blog/2014/05/29/fingerprinting-resolution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.b3rn3d.com/images/fingerprint.png" width="200">Fingerprinting attacks are ways of identifying individuals by some kind of attribute of their online activity. In some ways, fingerprinting attacks are the most dangerous and difficult type of de-anonymizing threats to defend against. I want to highlight one facet of fingerprinting that is used by many web services and organizations: screen resolution tracking.</p>

<p>In many cases, you have a laptop with a native screen resolution. This could be 1024x768, or 1900x1024, or some other combination. These resolutions point to the make and model of your laptop itself. The <a href="https://www.apple.com/macbook-pro/specs/">Macbook Pro</a> for instance has a native resolution of 1280x800. While there are many other laptops that run a similar resolution, you have shrunk down all of the possible systems that could be connecting to that of a system with that resolution. Imagine what a forensic investigator could do with this information.</p>

<p>This is even more dangerous on mobile devices such as Android. Each manufacturer releases new phones and tablets with different resolution, these are often very odd screen resolutions, making them very unique to that phone time. There are dozens of sites that provide this information for you:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_displays_by_pixel_density">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_displays_by_pixel_density</a></li>
<li><a href="https://deviceatlas.com/">https://deviceatlas.com/</a></li>
<li><a href="http://wurfl.sourceforge.net/">http://wurfl.sourceforge.net/</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Background</h2>

<p>There are two types of fingerprinting; passive and active. Active fingerprinting attacks are usually reserved to those that are collecting information about your network traffic, and do a secondary correlation. For example, if an adversary were running multiple exit nodes, they collect the list of sites each circuit connects to, and tries correlates that to a specific user.</p>

<p>Active attacks will manipulate or inject an identifier into your traffic &ndash; an identifying cookie or malicious JavaScript that when executed tries to collect identifying information about your browsing environment.</p>

<p>This is not a new revelation, the EFF has highlighted this problem by making the <a href="https://panopticlick.eff.org/">Panopticlick</a> project. This simulates attacks that aim at fingerprinting your browser, its plugins, fonts installed, etc. This is similar to the <a href="http://browserspy.dk/">BrowserSpy</a> project.</p>

<h2>Screen Resolution</h2>

<p>While we&rsquo;ve found ways to defend ourself against a variety of attacks (e.g. detecting the plugins we have installed by disabling JavaScript), defending yourself against tracking your screen resolution becomes more difficult. You should note here that screen resolution is the actual resolution of your computer screen, not just your browser window.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s a simple Javascript example that does that</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>&lt;a href="javascript:alert
</span><span class='line'>('Your resolution is '+screen.width+'x'+screen.height);">
</span><span class='line'>Screen Resolution Example&lt;/A></span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Demo: <a href="javascript:alert
('Your resolution is '+screen.width+'x'+screen.height);">
Screen Resolution Detection Example</A></p>

<p>EDIT: <a href="www.reddit.com/user/lugh">lugh</a> points out that this example is inconsistent and depends on your OS and browser.</p>

<h2>Defense Measures</h2>

<p>There are a couple of ways of defending, let me go over some possibilities:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>disabling Javascript</strong>: CSS (AFAIK) does not have a way of detecting your screen resolution</li>
<li><strong>resizing your browser window</strong>: Sometimes attacks do not read screen resolution, but just window size.</li>
<li><strong>changing your screen resolution</strong>: This is often difficult but by choosing a screen resolution that many other users may have, would help defend against fingerprinting. The <a href="http://dee.su/liberte-security">Liberte Linux</a> distribution is the only system I&rsquo;ve seen that automatically does this by forcing the screen resolution of 800x600.</li>
<li><strong>external monitors</strong>: If you are on a laptop, and have an external monitor around, it might be possible to have its resolution provide instead of your laptop screen. Note here that different operating systems handle this value in different ways. Some append the width and height of both screens to eachother.</li>
<li><strong>modifying the JavaScript engine</strong>: This solution has not been done very often and is considered a security risk, but there is a possibility that a new custom JavaScript engine could return a different value than your actual resolution.</li>
<li><strong>virtualization</strong>: If you are running your anonymous environment inside of a virtual machine, you can dynamically change the resolution very easily by resizing the window of the VM.</li>
</ul>


<p>There are different situations that heed different defense. If you run into a site you need access to that requires JavaScript, you&rsquo;re not going to be able to disable it. Same applies for the browser window trick if the service is detecting Screen.height as opposed to Window.height. Going into your screen settings and changing your screen resolution might work, but it&rsquo;s pretty cumbersome. The virtualization option is very plausible but requires that you are running virtualization software like Virtual Box.</p>

<h2>Real-World Attacks</h2>

<p>One example of software designed for fingerprinting is <a href="http://www.juniper.net/us/en/products-services/security/webapp-secure/">Juniper&rsquo;s Webapp Secure</a>. It is a tool that will fingerprint a web site&rsquo;s users based on a variety of metrics; one of which is your computer&rsquo;s resolution. By doing so, they are able to track their browsing experience across multiple sessions without any cookies.</p>

<h2>Applying to Registration</h2>

<p>Screen resolution is just a single attribute that can be keyed on but I find that it is relied upon the most often during web provider registration processes. This may be because the providers don&rsquo;t believe that anyone would go through the steps of changing their screen resolution &ndash; I&rsquo;m not sure. In any event, by merely changing your screen resolution, you are able to easily register without the stigma of anything you have done in a previous sessions possibly fingerprinting you. This along with clearing your cookies, connecting with a different IP address, and possibly manipulating the fonts that are installed on your computer will let you bypass the registration process&hellip;. sometimes.</p>

<h2>Conclusions</h2>

<p>If nothing else, I provide this as a reminder that your screen resolution is often a hard-coded, highly identifiable value you should actively defend against leaking to unknown parties. While not as identifying as say something like your MAC address, it remains a highly attributable value. Imagine a scenario where an adversary is correlating the online activity of someone visiting a site with a resolution of 1870x1300. Even if you&rsquo;ve securely erased your system before a forensic investigator has arrived, they will be able to easily notice that your laptop&rsquo;s screen resolution is 1870x1300. And because this resolution is highly unusual, it&rsquo;s a simple step to make the correlation between your laptop and its traffic.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
